■
本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址http://shinybbs.com
■
翻译： 麦禾禾禾禾 CCC 风与大脸猫 柒一四
翻译： 借了米 汤汤 艾绒 Passenger ghostbear
■
校对： 柒一四     后期： 小滔
ShinY
深影
■
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 shinybbs.com
深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub
美国狙击手
真他妈热
It's a fucking hotbox.
见鬼的尘土跟狗屎一个味
Man, the fucking dirt here tastes like dog shit.
- 你得吃过狗屎才知道 不是吗 - 闭嘴
- Oh, well, you'd know, wouldn't you? - Shut the fuck up.
这有个兵役年龄的男性
I got a military-age male
一边看着护卫队一边打着电话 完毕
that's on a cell phone watching the convoy, over.
要是你觉得他在报告连队动向
If you think he's reporting troop movement,
允许射杀 由你决定 完毕
you have a green light. Your call. Over.
没准他只是在跟老妈通话
Maybe he's just calling his old lady.
他下楼了
He stepped off.
等下 发现一个女人和小孩
Hold on. I got a woman and a kid,
在二百码以外 正向护卫队方向移动
200 yards out, moving towards the convoy.
她没有摆臂 怀里有东西
Her arms aren't swinging. She's carrying something.
她拿着个手榴弹
Yeah, she's got a grenade.
一个RKG俄国制手榴弹 刚刚递给那个孩子了
She's got an RKG Russian grenade she just handed to the kid.
你说女人和小孩
You say a woman and a kid?
你注意到了吗 能否批准射击
You got eyes on this? Can you confirm?
拒绝 你知道交战协定的 由你决定
Negative. You know the R.O.E. Your call.
要是你弄错了他们会吃了你的
Man, they fry you if you're wrong.
他们会把你派到莱文沃思
They send your ass to Leavenworth.
打中了
You got him.
回来
Hey, get back here!
- 永远不要把枪丢下 - 是 先生
- You don't ever leave your rifle in the dirt. - Yes, sir.
那一枪射的不错 你有天分
That was a hell of a shot, son. You got a gift.
有一天你会成为一个优秀的猎手
You're gonna make a fine hunter someday.
在《使徒行传》中
Here in the book of acts,
有好几次 保罗为了信仰
several times, Paul stands in judgment
而面对审判
for what he believes.
这种情况时有发生 我们都要面对
And at times, we all have to do that.
我是说 我们没有他的眼界
I mean, we don't see with his eyes,
所以不能理解他计划的恢宏
so we don't know the glory of his plan.
生命的展开就如镜中令人不解的倒影
Our lives unfold before us like puzzling reflections in a mirror.
- 你干嘛呢 - 而当我们悟道那天
- What are you doing? - And on the day we rise...
我们将看清并懂得他一路上的神秘
we will see with clarity and understand the mystery of his ways.
祈祷吧
Let us pray.
这世上有三种人
There are three types of people in this world...
羊 狼 和牧羊犬
sheep, wolves, and sheepdogs.
有些人更愿意相信
Now, some people prefer to
世上并无邪恶
believe that evil doesn't exist in the world.
若有一天邪恶降临
And if it ever darkened their doorstep,
他们将无法自保
they wouldn't know how to protect themselves.
这些人是羊
Those are the sheep.
然后是捕食者们
And then you got predators.
他们用暴力捕食弱者 这是狼
They use violence to prey on the weak. They're the wolves.
接下来 还有那些
And then there are those
生来就幸运地拥有进攻能力
who've been blessed with the gift of aggression
与不可抵抗的保护欲
and the overpowering need to protect the flock.
这些人是能与狼对垒的稀有品种
These men are the rare breed that live to confront the wolf.
他们是牧羊犬
They are the sheepdog.
我们家不养懦弱的羊
Now, we're not raising any sheep in this family.
而若你们变成狼 我会让你们死得好看
And I will whup your ass if you turn into a wolf.
韦恩
Wayne.
但是 我们保护自己
But we protect our own.
要是有人想和你打架
Now, if someone tries to fight you
或者欺负你弟弟
or tries to bully your little brother,
我允许你们下狠手
you have my permission to finish it.
那家伙欺负杰夫
The guy was picking on Jeff.
- 真的吗 - 是 先生 是真的
- Is that true? - Yes, sir. Yes, he was.
你下了狠手吗
Did you finish it?
那么你知道自己是谁
Well, then you know who you are.
你知道自己的目的
You know your purpose.
克里斯·凯尔今晚将挑战的马匹是"超级情妇"
Chris Kyle is on the horse Big Mistress here this evening.
没什么问题
You're all right.
现在 准备
Now, get ready.
很好
That's good.
今晚他需要挑战目前最高分86分
So, tonight, he needs to beat the leading score of 86.
嗨 杰夫 好像你哥哥又成功了
Hey, Jeff. Looks like your brother did it again.
克里斯·凯尔
...Chris Kyle.
那又不是没人 你拿着条皮带就出来了
Man, wasn't nobody there. You come out with a belt buckle.
你要拿它干嘛
What are you supposed to do with it?
用它勾人上床啊
Supposed to get laid with it.
我会系上它 看看能不能让莎拉兴奋起来
I'm gonna wear it and see if it puts Sarah in the mood.
妈的 一阵强风都能让她兴奋
Shit, a strong wind'll put Sarah in the mood.
是这样吗
Oh, is that what they say?
你知道高中时候她外号是什么
Man, you know what they called her in high school.
- 好吧 别说出来 - 莎拉吸了好多
- All right. Don't say it. - Sarah sucks-a-lotta...
- 我说什么了 -  操 克里斯
- What'd I say? - Shit, Chris.
见鬼
Goddamn it.
- 那是竞技的所得 那两个姑娘 那就是为何 - 不
- That was bucking money, those two girls. And that's why... - No.
他一直在盯着她看
He kept looking... he had his eyes on her,
那就是为什么 上次
and that's why, the last time...
- 你等会 看看这皮带什么效果 - 好
- Wait till you see what this does. - Yeah.
那就是我 蠢货
That's me, you dog.
宝贝 想不想和竞技明星来一发 什么情况
Hey, baby. Who wants to fuck a rodeo star? What the fuck?
你说你明天才到家
You said you wasn't coming home until tomorrow.
- 我说什么了 - 不 我只是没...
- I said what? - No, I just didn't...
克里斯 别动他 好吗 他什么也没做
Chris, just leave him alone, all right? He didn't do anything!
- 我什么都不知道 救命 - 克里斯 别动他
- I didn't know shit, man. Help! - Chris, leave him alone!
他妈的克里斯 别动他
Fucking Chris, leave him alone!
真见鬼 你有什么毛病
Goddamn it! What is wrong with you?
他不知道 好吗
He didn't know, all right?
哦 他不知道 你不知道什么啊
Oh, he didn't know? What didn't you know?
- 把帽子给我 - 把他帽子拿来 宝贝
- Just give me my hat. - Get his hat, baby.
他不知道什么 你以为那些来复枪是谁的
He didn't know what? Whose rifles did you think those were?
你以为那些男人的衣服是她的吗
Those clothes, them men's clothes weren't hers?
你不知道这些吗
Is that what you didn't know?
你这他妈到底怎么了
What the fuck is wrong with you?!
他妈的你不用对谁都挥拳头
You don't have to fucking punch everyone!
带上你的帽子 给我滚
Put that fucking hat on and get the fuck out.
你他妈有什么毛病
What the fuck is wrong with you?
滚
Get out.
你知道吗 我不知道你对我有什么期待
You know what? I don't know what you expect from me.
你把我拖到这来
You drag me out here and then
然后每周末你都和你弟弟去逍遥
you run off with your brother every damn weekend.
你以为我为什么这么做
Why do you think I did this?
我这么做是为了得到你的注意 你不懂吗
I do this to get attention! Don't you get that?
拿上你的东西 滚
Get your stuff and get out.
好 好 你知道么 去你的
Fine. Fine. You know what? Fuck you. Fine.
你以为玩竞技你就是牛仔了吗
You think you're a cowboy 'cause you rodeo.
你不是牛仔 你就是个烦人的农场工
You're not a cowboy. You're just a lousy ranch hand.
还是个差劲的床伴
And you're a shitty fucking lay.
别说出来
Don't say it.
婚礼是什么时候
When's the wedding?
我明白你说的 但是
I understand what you're saying, but...
你知道的 我们得穿过整个州
you know, we get to travel over the whole state.
每周末都在不同的城市
Different city every weekend.
野马和小公牛
Broncs and steers.
- 我不知道 但也许她是对的呢 - 她是对的
- I don't know. Maybe she's right, though. - She's right?
哪件事对了 克里斯 她才不对 我们是牛仔啊
Right about what, Chris? She's not right, man. We're cowboys.
- 我们在实现梦想 - 特别报道
- We're living the dream. - This is a special report.
在坦桑尼亚首都达累斯萨拉姆 和肯尼亚首都内罗比
Those explosions set to go off at the U.S. Embassies
所发生的美国大使馆爆炸事件
in Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania, and Nairobi, Kenya,
明显是某势力对美国的宣战
were clearly a part of someone's war against the United States.
今日 有超过八十人在这两起爆炸中丧生
More than 80 dead, more than
超过一千七百人受伤
1,700 injured in two bomb blasts today...
嘿 杰夫 杰夫 嘿
Hey, Jeff. Jeff. Hey.
- 相距250英里 - 看看这个
- ...250 miles apart. - Look at this.
现在我们还不清楚敌人是谁
It is still unclear at this hour who our enemy is.
尽管很明显 事件的目标是大使馆
Although the embassies were obviously the targets...
- 看看他们所做的 - 受伤的不全是美国人
- Look what they did to us. - ...and injured are not Americans.
仍然有八名美国人 包括一个孩子 丧生了
Still, eight Americans, including one child, are dead,
还有五人失踪
and five are still missing.
军事职业中心
- 你是德克萨斯州来的 - 是的 先生
- So, you're from Texas. - Yes, sir.
- 你是个爱国者 - 是的 先生
- You're a patriot. - Yes, sir.
- 你气坏了 - 我想派上用场
- And you're pissed off. - I'm looking to be of service.
- 你喜欢打架 - 是的 先生
- You like to fight? - Yes, sir.
你喜欢打架 那好
You like to fight. Okay. Well...
为什么不考虑下精英战队呢
Why don't you meet the warrior elite?
- 海豹突击队 - 是的 海 空 陆
- SEALs. - Yep. Sea, air, and land.
我水性不太好 先生
Well, I'm not much for the water, sir.
不吗 这可不是头脑一热就行的
No? Well, this ain't for the faint-a heart.
大多数人 被淘汰 就放弃了
Most men, they wash out, they quit.
我可不是大多数人 我不会放弃的
But I'm not most men, sir. I don't quit.
- 好日子到头啦 小伙子们 - 坚持住 姑娘们 坚持住
- This is where the fun stops, guys! - Take it, girls! Take it!
坚持住 坚持住 坚持住 只有第一次会疼
That's it, girls. Take it. Take it. Only hurts the first time.
这是怎么了 你放弃了吗 孩子
What we got here? You a quitter, boy?
呼呀 为海豹突击队队员的战斗口号
呼呀 没有 罗尔教官
Hooyah, no, Instructor Rolle.
放屁 要不是我发现了 你他妈就是个偷懒的货
Bullshit! Yo ass is fleet meat if I ever did see it!
别转过去
Don't turn away from me, son.
看着我 给我忍着
You look at me and you take this shit.
- 呼呀 长官 - 见鬼 你真他妈老
- Hooyah, sir! - Damn, you old as fuck!
你加入海军是因为
You join the Navy 'cause you
在诺亚方舟上玩的挺开心是么
had such a good goddamn time on Noah's ark?
- 你多大了 - 呼呀 三十
- How old are you, boy? - Hooyah, 30!
三十 你都够给这里的一半孩子当爹了
30? Your fart dust could have fathered half these boys.
我们会把半途而废的人都剔除的
We gonna weed through the quitters.
今天 我们就能发现一两个好战士了
Yeah, we gonna find us a goddamn warrior or two today.
多贝 你确定你是从康奈迪克州来的吗
Dauber, are you sure you're from Connecticut?
我还没见过从哈特福特[康奈迪克州首府]来的乡巴佬呢
I ain't never met no hick from Hartford before.
呼呀 弗雷迪教官 国家是全国人民的国家
Hooyah, instructor Fredy! Country's countrywide.
我是来这消灭恐怖分子的
I came here to kill terrorists.
谁他妈让你笑了
Who the fuck told your ass to giggle?
呼呀 没人 罗尔教官
Hooyah, no one, instructor Rolle!
我让你张嘴了吗
Did I ask you to open up your mouth?
呼呀 没有 罗尔教官
Hooyah, no, instructor Rolle.
看看你这又胖又软还傻笑的混蛋
Look at your fat, pasty, giggly ass.
见鬼 你个喝饮料吃零食的混账
Damn, son! You a big Dr. Pepper, cheeto-eating motherfucker.
是 我就是这意思
Yeah. That's what I'm talking about.
Biggles=Bitch+Giggly 婊子加傻笑
比格斯 从今天起这就是你的名字了
Biggles. That's your name from now on,
这也是你回家的机票
sunshine. And that's your ticket home.
迪 你怎么还在我的队里
"D"! What are you still doing in my line,
还想试着合格吗
trying to make this team?
谁都知道黑人不擅长游泳
Everybody knows black guys don't swim.
没事 长官 我不是黑人
It's all right, sir. I'm not black.
- 不是吗 - 不 我是新新黑人
- No? - No. I'm the new black.
我们跑得慢 跳得低 游得好 还去盖璞买衣服
We run slow, we jump low, we swim good, and we shop at gap.
我还能靠着弄湿他们老婆
And I make the white folk proud
而让白人兄弟们骄傲一下 我完全征服了他们
when I hose down their ladies. I dick 'em down!
呼呀
Hooyah!
那个 那就是半途而废的人
There it is! That is a quitter.
你跟他告别 我却觉得终于解脱了
You say goodbye, I say good riddance.
他现在在这背弃你 就会在战场上会背弃你
He quits on you here, he's gonna quit in the field of battle.
当出现情况时 他不会挺身而出
When shit gets hairy, he won't step up.
你被击中了 他不会把你拉起来
Your ass gets shot, he won't pull you out.
我在寻找的是战士
I'm looking for warriors!
- 七 - 接着数
- Seven! - Keep counting!
- 八 - 我听不到 - 九
- Eight! - I can't hear you! - Nine!
想让我给你妈打电话吗 废物
You want me to call your mama, old man?
没准她能来代替你呢
Maybe she could come and take your place.
这只是前戏 我马上
This is foreplay! I'm about
放点马文·盖伊的歌 这才真正开始呢
to turn on some Marvin Gaye and get in that ass!
我就是这个意思
That's what I'm talking about!
松鼠又指经常口交的人 因为他们嘴里总塞满了坚果(又有精子的含义)
松鼠 松鼠 松鼠 你的松子在哪儿呢
Squirrel, Squirrel, Squirrel, where the fuck are your nuts?
它们永远消失了 长官  它们爬回里面去了
Oh, they're gone for good, sir. They crawled back up inside.
但是它们是暖的
But they are warm.
小人说大话
Big talk from a little man!
你呢 你怎么样 老年人
Now you. How about you, old man?
你感觉如何
How you feeling?
呼呀 很危险 我感觉有危险
Hooyah, dangerous. Feeling dangerous.
呼呀 凯尔感觉很危险
Hooyah! Kyle's feeling dangerous.
冲啊
Move!
坐下
Take seats!
妈的 十三度 海水如此新鲜 如此干净
Damn! 56 degrees, so fresh, so clean.
再坚持几个小时 你们就是海豹突击队队员了
Only a few more hours, and you're Navy SEALs!
- 只有我能命中靶心 所以 - 是的
- I'm the only one who's hit one, so... - Yeah.
- 不错 - 克里斯 该你了
- Oh, yeah. - Chris, your turn, man.
- 不 你再来一次 - 再来一次 好吧
- No, you got one more. - I got one more? All right.
好的 再投一个 来了 来了
All right. One more. Here we go. Here we go.
我们要个小点儿的靶子 伙计 用你的胳膊吧
Hey, we want a smaller target, we'll use your arm, man.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hi.
你好吗
How you doing?
我还好 谢谢你
Good. Thank you.
能请你喝一杯吗
Can I... get you a drink?
一杯酒能让你高到一米八 还是让你有魅力
Will a drink make you six inches taller and charming?
- 会让你单身吗 - 我没有
- Will it make you not married? - I'm not...
我刚看见你摘掉戒指 好吗
Yeah. I just watched you take your ring off, okay?
别做个混蛋 回家吧
Don't be a scumbag. Go home.
噢 我的天
Oh, my God.
- 这可能是皮裤的原因 - 哦 是吗
- It may have been the leather pants. - Oh, yeah?
一个女孩要穿什么样的裤子才能避免骚扰
What kind of pants does a girl have to wear to be left alone?
也许是灯芯绒裤子
Well, maybe corduroy.
我的意思是 你们男人都这幅德行吗
I mean, is that how it is with you guys?
难道喝了三杯酒你们就突然变成单身了
You're, like, suddenly single after three beers?
不会 喝了三杯之后 我就只想着第四杯
Oh, no. After three beers, all I know is to get a fourth.
这不错 不错 真正的乡巴佬
Oh, that's great. That's great. Real redneck.
我不是乡巴佬 我来自德克萨斯州
Oh, I'm not a redneck. I'm from Texas.
这两者有什么不同
What's the difference?
我们骑马 而他们骑他们的表亲
Well, we ride horses and they ride their cousins.
你是干什么的 你很明显是军人
What do you do for work? You're obviously military.
我清理那些被圈养的海豚
I polish dolphins. They're in captivity.
就是擦掉它们身上的甲壳虫
What I do is just sort of scrape off the crustaceans.
- 你看我傻吗 - 不傻 事实上你看起来有点悲伤
- Do I look stupid to you? - No. Honestly, you look a little sad.
我的身高是否可以请你喝酒了
Am I... tall enough to buy you a drink?
除非你告诉我你是干什么的
Not until you tell me what you do.
好吧 你看这样行吗 嗨 格雷格
Okay. How about this? Hey, Greg?
给我来两杯 问一个问题喝一杯如何
Get two shots. How 'bout we do a shot for a question?
每次你问我答
Every time you ask me a question and I answer,
然后你就喝一杯 反之亦然
you got to do a shot. Same, vice versa.
游戏开始
Game on.
你可以把这瓶酒也留在这 好了 问吧
You can leave the bottle, too. Okay, shoot.
好的 把你很明显是军人 哪个部队的
All right. You're obviously military. What branch?
我刚刚完成了基本水中爆破训练 要去狙击学校了
I just finished BUD/S, heading to sniper school.
- 开玩笑吗 你是海豹突击队的 - 是的 女士
- Are you kidding me? You're a SEAL? - Yes, ma'am.
- 这是两个问题 - 该死
- That's two questions. - Shit.
真的吗
Really?
你没必要真的喝完
Oh, I didn't really mean you had to do that.
好吧 见鬼了
Okay. Shit.
我了解你们这些家伙 我姐姐和一名海豹突击队的订婚了
I know all about you guys. My sister was engaged to a SEAL.
- 真的吗 - 是的
- Oh, was she? - Yeah.
等等 你怎么会了解所有人的 你是什么意思
Hold on. How you know all about us? What do you mean?
我的意思是 你们是一群狂妄自大
What I mean is, you're a bunch of arrogant,
以自我为中心的蠢货 以为自己可以撒谎
self-centered pricks who think you can lie
可以欺骗 可以为所欲为
and cheat and do whatever
我永远不会和海豹突击队的人约会的
the fuck you want. I'd never date a SEAL.
等一下 你为什么说我是以自我为中心的人
Wait. Why would you say I'm self-centered?
我愿意为国家献出生命
I'd lay down my life for my country.
为什么
Why?
因为它是世界上最伟大的国家
'Cause it's the greatest country on earth,
我会不惜一切去保护它
and I'd do everything I can to protect it.
我对你姐姐的遭遇表示遗憾 但我不是这样的人
Look, I'm sorry what happened to your sister, but that's not me.
- 很高兴见到你 - 你要去哪里
- It's nice to meet you. - Where are you going?
呃 我只是要回家了
Well, I was just gonna go home
因为你不想和海豹突击队员约会 所以
because you said you wouldn't date a SEAL, so...
我是说我永远都不会和他们结婚
I said I'd never marry one.
好吧 那也许
Oh, okay. Well, then maybe,
你好 很高兴遇见你 你叫什么名字
hello. Nice to meet you. What's your name?
- 我叫塔娅 - 塔娅
- Taya. - Taya.
克里斯 我叫克里斯·凯尔 很高兴见到你 很荣幸
Chris. I'm Chris Kyle. Nice to meet you. Pleasure.
我的意思是 这种想法很自负
I mean, it's pretty egotistical of
认为你可以保护我们所有人 不是吗 克里斯
you to think you can protect us all. Isn't it, Chris?
我们的训练指挥官说有三...
Well, our BUD/S officer commander said that it's three...
好吧 他说有三件事
Okay. He said there's three
我们得担心 分别是自我 酒和女人
things we got to worry about: Ego, booze, and women.
听起来你受到夹击了
Well, sounds like you're under attack.
你真美
You're pretty.
还很可爱
You're so cute.
我帮你
I got you.
我不会和你回家的 所以想都别想
I'm not going home with you, so don't even think about it.
感受呼吸充满你们体内的每一个细胞
Feel breath filling every cell in your body.
这是我们该有的习惯
This is our ritual.
控制自己的呼吸和思想
We master our breath, we master our mind.
扣动机板将会成为你下意识的动作
Pulling the trigger will become an unconscious effort.
你会意识到自己开了枪 但是不去控制它
You will be aware of it, but not directing it.
在你呼气的时候 找到你呼吸间的停顿
And as you exhale, find your natural respiratory pause
还有心脏跳动的间隙
and the space between heartbeats.
你好 我是塔娅 我现在不在
Hey. This is Taya. I can't get to the phone.
请留言 我会回电的
Leave a message. I'll call you back.
嗨 又是我 那个被你吐脏鞋子的家伙
Hey, it's me again. The guy whose shoes you puked on.
我在想
So... yeah, I was thinking
或许你没收到最后那条信息
maybe you didn't get that last message,
我发的最后一条信息 或者
the last message I left, or...
倒数第二条 所以我认为
the one before that. So I figured that...
- 你认为什么 - 你好吗 你过得怎么样
- You figured what? - Hey. How are you? How've you been?
我过得不错
Good.
很好 哇 你在忙什么
Good. Wow. What are you up to?
没忙什么 你呢
Not a lot. You?
不 只是 和你说话很兴奋
No, just... excited to talk to you.
目标越小 偏差越小
Aim small, miss small.
如果你瞄准一颗衬衫纽扣 你可能会有2英寸的偏差
If you aim for a shirt button, you might miss by 2 inches.
如果你瞄准他的衬衫 你可能会有2尺的偏差
If you aim for his shirt, you might miss by 2 feet.
- 你最好集中一个点打 凯尔 - 是的 长官
- You better close those groupings, Kyle. - Yes, sir.
老天
God.
- 还不错 我们能得到哪种 - 最上面一层的
- Not bad. What do we get for that? - Top shelf.
- 我喜欢那个棕色的 - 好的 给你
- I like that one. Brown one. - Sure. Here you go.
- 太棒了 谢谢你 祝你开心 - 看啊 谢谢
- Great. Thank you, sir. Have a good day. - Oh, look! Thank you.
- 你好 - 很好 它和你很配
- Hello. - Oh, good. That looks good on you.
你是一直想成为一名士兵吗
So, did you always want to be a soldier?
不 我想成为一名牛仔 但是
No. I wanted to be a cowboy, but...
不知道 我曾是牛仔 想着我注定要做些大事
I don't know. I did that. Thought I was meant for something more.
所以你开始在酒吧救助女孩
So you started rescuing girls from bars?
我认为我从你手里救下了那间酒吧
I think I rescued that bar from you.
- 你喜欢乡村音乐吗 - 只有在我情绪低落时
- You like country music? - Only when I'm depressed.
- 那孩子呢 你想要孩子吗 - 想要 有一天吧
- How about kids? You want kids? - Yeah, someday.
我妈妈说我有一只专门挑选渣男的鼻子
My mom says I have a nose for picking the wrong men.
好吧 这样说一个女孩可不太好了
Well, that's a shitty thing to say to a girl.
嗯 我已经了证明她是对的
Well, I've proven her right.
那些错误的选择让你出现在这儿
Them wrong picks put you here,
让你成为了你 我喜欢这样的你
made you who you are. I like who you are.
你是否想过如果一个活生生的人
You ever think about what happens
站在你的枪口时会发生什么吗
when there's a real person on the end of that gun?
不知道 只希望当那天到来时我能做好我的工作
I don't know. I just hope I can do my job when that day comes.
我们看的是同一个靶子吗 你在射灰尘
Are we looking at the same target? You're spitting dust.
不过别担心
And don't worry.
不会射击的家伙还是可以当医护兵的
We can always use corpsmen for the guys who can't shoot.
操
Oh, fuck.
- 你在发抖 - 我知道
- You're trembling. - I know it.
- 我们不必做这件事 如果你不 - 不 我想做 我要做
- We don't have to do this if you don't... - No, I want to. I do.
- 真的 - 感觉你太真实 这让我害怕
- Yeah? - You just feel real and it scares me.
你把眼睛闭着了吗
You got your off-eye shut?
如果我闭着眼 那我就看不到那边的东西了
Well, if I close my off-eye, then I can't see what's out there.
那里除了靶子什么都没有
There's nothing out there but the target.
不 长官 那还有别的东西
Negative. Sir, there is something out there.
打它
Punch it.
做俯卧撑会让你打中吗 做五十个 凯尔 明确又安全
Will push-ups help? Give me 50, Kyle. Clear and safe.
我更擅长打活的
I'm better when it's breathing.
- 又出现了一架 - 天呀 克里斯
- ...what appears to be another... - Oh, my God. Chris!
- 怎么了 - 不
- What's wrong? - No!
这是录像带 大家看到第一架
Here's the tape. You see the first
飞机似乎从东边飞过来
plane coming in from what looks like the east side.
然后冒着火撞上了大厦
And it goes into the building with the flames
浓烟从双子塔的另一端翻滚而出
and the smoke billowing out the other side of the tower.
我很难说清
It's hard for me to tell exactly
那一边是北边 那一边是南边
which is the north side and which is the south side.
但可以看出浓烟是从北边冒出
But it appears it's coming out of the north side there.
几分钟以前 这些令人震惊的影像
And then, moments ago, these incredible images.
我相信这是第一个
I believe that's the first one.
这是南边大厦倾塌的画面
That's the south tower collapsing.
它就像一座
It almost looks like one
你见过的那些被爆破的建筑
of those implosions of buildings that you see,
除了一件事
except there is nothing
这次没有人控制它爆破 这是一场灾难
controlled about this. This is devastation.
你甚至都不了解我
You don't even know me.
我了解的够多了 你是打包出售的 宝贝
I know enough. You are a package deal, babe.
- 你在害怕什么 - 没什么
- What are you so afraid of? - Nothing.
害怕所有的事 我不知道 如果我的害怕解决不了呢
Everything. I don't know. What if it doesn't work out?
我们会结婚 然后组建一个家庭
We're gonna get married and then we're gonna start a family.
你计划好了一切 不是吗
You got it all planned out, don't you?
我计划好了
I'm done.
我爱你
I love you.
如果你要聊那些的话
Well, you're gonna need a ring
你得先有一枚戒指
if you want to talk all tough like that.
好吧
Okay.
女士们 先生们 克里斯·凯尔夫妇
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. And Mrs. Chris Kyle!
你脖子上是什么鬼东西
What the hell is on your neck?
你的脖子上好像浇了绿漆在身上
Your neck. You've got, like, green paint all over you.
你相信我吗 宝贝 如果我告诉你我刚打了针
Would you believe me, babe, if I told you I had an I.V.
两个小时前我全身都是绿色
and I was all green about two hours ago?
你是 什么
What are you... what?
- 反悔也晚了 宝贝 - 噢 天呀
- It's a package deal, babe. - Oh, my God.
来这
Come here, you.
为他们干杯
Cheers to that.
什么情况 长官
What's the word, chief?
刚收到消息 男孩儿们 开始了
Just got the call, boys. It's on!
呼呀
Hooyah!
干杯
Shots!
爽
Yes!
五杯酒
Five shots.
- 只有六个星期 宝贝 - 我太害怕了 亲爱的
- It's only gonna be six weeks, baby. - I'm so afraid, baby.
这是他们说的 你什么都不用害怕
That's what they say. You got nothing to be afraid of.
- 那你 - 这是计划的一部分
- What are you... - It's all part of the plan.
你的心脏都要跳出来了
Your heart is beating out of your chest.
这是因为我不是
That's just 'cause I'm not
唯一一个要去参战的人 就是这样
the only one that's going to war. That's all.
干杯
Cheers!
第一次派遣
欢迎来到费卢杰 老中东的新狂野西部
Welcome to Fallujah. The new wild west of the old Middle East.
基地组织在悬赏你们的脑袋
AQI put a price on your heads,
现在全球的极端主义者都涌入
and now extremists from around the globe
边境地区想取你们的脑袋 你们狙击手
are flooding the borders to collect on it. You snipers...
你们会和一名海军士兵组队
you're gonna be paired with a marine
他会掩护你 你们会安插在大路旁
to watch your back and inserted along the main road
为海军第一师逐户搜查做掩护
to do overwatch for 1st marines going door to door.
你们的工作就是不惜一切代价保护他们
Your job is to protect those marines at all costs.
这座城市已经被疏散了
This city has been evacuated.
留在这的所有兵役年龄的男性 都是来杀你的
Any military-age male who is still here... is here to kill you.
保证这些士兵的安全 然后活着回家
Let's bring these boys in safe and get our asses back home.
出来 出来 出来
Out, out, out!
我得小心点 特克斯
I'd keep that head down, Tex.
穆斯林也有狙击手 你知道的
Muj got snipers, too, you know.
狙击手不会瞄准你的脑袋
A sniper won't aim for your head.
伙计 他们有个狙击手
Man, they got this one sniper
能在五百码[约450米]外一枪暴头
that's been hitting head shots from 500 yards out.
人称穆斯塔法
They call him Mustafa.
他还参加了奥运会
He's in the Olympics.
现在奥运会有狙击项目了吗
They got sniping in the Olympics now?
等下  发现一个女人和小孩
Hold on. I got a woman and a kid,
二百码外 正向车队方向移动
200 yards out, moving towards the convoy.
她没有摆臂 怀里有东西
Her arms aren't swinging. She's carrying something.
她拿着个手榴弹
She's got a grenade. She's got
一个RKG俄国制手榴弹 刚刚递给那个孩子了
an RKG Russian grenade she just handed to the kid.
你说女人和小孩
You say a woman and a kid?
你注意到了吗 能否批准射击
You got eyes on this? Can you confirm?
拒绝 你知道交战规则 由你决定
Negative. You know the R.O.E. Your call.
要是你弄错了他们会吃了你的
Man, they fry you if you're wrong.
他们会把你派到莱文沃思
They send your ass to Leavenworth.
靠 枪法真棒
Fuck, that was gnarly.
邪恶的婊子
Fucking evil bitch.
起来 继续前进
Get up. Keep moving.
射得漂亮 特克斯 正确的决定
Nice shooting, Tex. Hell of a call.
收到了 做得好
Roger that. Good looking out, Navy.
- 靠 你刚听到了吗 - 他妈的别碰我
- Fuck, did you hear that, man? - Get the fuck off me.
人都去哪了
Where is everybody?
都出去找乐子了
We're just checking our dicks here, man.
训练那些见鬼的伊斯兰士兵
We're training those fucking Hajji soldiers.
那你怎么不去
Yeah, why aren't you out there?
- 我有这些好东西了 - 什么 看漫画书
- Well, I have the shits. - What, reading a comic book?
这他妈的是绘画小说 区别大了
It's a fucking graphic novel, man. There's a big difference.
我听说你今天开枪了
I heard you were on fucking fire out there.
马克·李进来说你今天开了第一枪 是吗
Marc Lee came in, said you popped your cherry. Is that right?
那还是个孩子 毛都没长齐
There was a kid who... barely had any hair on his balls.
母亲给了他一个手榴弹
Mother gives him a grenade,
叫他去杀海军陆战队
sends him out there to kill marines.
老兄 这真是前所未见的可恶
Dude, that's evil like I never seen before.
但是 伙计
Yeah. But, hey, man,
你知道那孩子可能会
you know that kid could
夺走十个海军士兵的生命
have taken out like 10 fucking marines, right?
但是我杀了他
Yeah, but I killed him.
你做了你的工作 这就是故事的结局
You did your job. That's the end of the story.
只是和我预想的第一个不一样
Yeah, it's just not how I envisioned that first one to go down.
莱利 好了 没有现货
Riley, it's okay. Don't have the actuals.
老兄 搞什么鬼
Fuck, man! What the hell?
那是你的哨点 爱因斯坦 你可以等会再谢他
That was your overwatch, Einstein. You can thank him later.
前进
Let's move!
继续走
Keep going.
快点
Hurry up.
分散
Disperse!
停火 停火
Cease fire! Cease fire!
看着屋顶 盯着那别动
Eyes on the rooftop! Keep your eyes up there!
有人倒下 需要一个医疗兵
Man down! Man down! We need a corpsman over here now!
敌方狙击手已定位 大概坐标QR155604
Enemy sniper located. Approximate grid, Quebec-Romeo, 1-5-5-6-0-4.
- 这闻着一股尿骚味 - 好吧
- Smells like piss in here. - Yeah, well...
你掩护得很好 射得很有胆量
You covered our asses out there, man. Some ballsy shots.
- 他们被清理了吧 - 是的
- Fuck. They were clean, right? - Hell yeah, they were.
那见鬼的狙击手取了一条命
That fucking sniper went right up our ass!
我已经训斥过安全人员了
Yeah, I already chewed out security detail.
不会有下次了
It ain't gonna happen again.
最好如此
It better not happen again.
- 威胁依然存在 - 好吧
- There's a hot spot 400 meters out. - All right.
我会写个狙击报告
I'm gonna go write up some shooter statements.
- 你解决了几个人 - 六个 不对
- How many'd you get? - I got six... oh. No, that's not true.
是八个 但是他们拖回去两个
I got eight, but they dragged two off.
- 你解决了六个 - 怎么了
- You got six? - Yeah. Why? What's wrong?
没什么 你比其它狙击手加起来射的还多
Nothing. You just got more than the rest of the snipers combined.
但还是让他们打中我们一员
Yeah, but they got one of us.
你看不到也办法啊
You can't shoot what you can't see.
他的妻子说他带着本古兰经
His wife said he was carrying a Koran.
我不知道古兰经长什么样
Look, I don't know what a Koran looks like,
但我知道他带着什么
but I can tell you what he was carrying.
压制金属 7.62口径
It was pressed metal, shot 7.62s,
看起来就是把AK-47
and it looked just like an AK-47.
所以你告诉我他带着什么
So you tell me what he was carrying.
他来了 他来了
Oh, here he comes. Here he comes.
女士们先生们 听好了 我们当中出了个传奇人物
Ladies and genitals, listen up! We have a legend in our midst!
为我们的传奇喝彩
Round of applause for The Legend!
我们真为你感到骄傲 你保卫了家园
There we go. We're so proud of you back home on the range, boy.
据说这位传奇人物能
Now, it's been... it's been said that The Legend here
一下子干掉一百个人
can kill 100 men with one blow.
或者不 是...是什么来着
Or, no, it was... what was... nah, it was... fuck. What was it?
这个单身男人干了 他干了一百个人
It was one... one blow from a single man. He blew 100... men.
而且他还单身 该死的 见鬼
And he's single. And... Goddamn it! Shit!
见鬼
Oh, shit!
- 该死 - 我靠
- Damn, man. - Oh, fuck.
你想要来场食物大战吗 来吧
You want a food fight? Come on.
- 见鬼 - 只有这办法能让你闭嘴
- Shit. - Only way to shut you up.
你杀过人了吗
Have you killed anyone yet?
这可不是打电话回家时该聊的 宝贝
That is not the way the call home is supposed to go, babe.
不要觉得奇怪 真的
Don't be weird with me. Seriously.
我希望你能告诉我一切
I want you to tell me everything.
你肯定也有事是不能在电话里说的
Well, there's certain things you just can't say over the phone.
好吧 你让我怀孕对吧
Okay, you knocked me up, right?
然后我一个人坐在这按说明书装婴儿床
And I'm sitting here by myself literally assembling baby cribs,
你还不能和我说 这就是你的大计划
and you can't talk to me? That's your big plan?
你们的任务快要结束了吗
You guys almost done over there yet?
我忍不住一直在想
I can't stop thinking about
蜜月时你穿的那件粉色的小东西
that little pink number you wore on our honeymoon.
那叫睡衣
Yeah, it's called a nightgown.
没错
Yeah.
而且三天
And three days...
三天根本算不上蜜月
three days is not a honeymoon.
好吧 那真是美妙的三天
Well, it was a good three days.
我真的好想你
I miss you real bad.
我也想你
I miss you, too.
- 你想要我说些下流话吗 - 是啊
- Hey, you want me to talk dirty to you? - Yeah.
等下 等一秒种 我正好
Hold on. Hold on a second. Let me just...
一只手拿着手机 另一只手拿着枪
I got... A phone in one hand and a gun in the other,
所以我都不知道我要干什么了
so I don't know what I'm gonna do.
你得决定哪一个更重要 亲爱的
Well, you're gonna have to decide what's more important, baby.
你真是淫荡的孕妇
Oh, you're a horny preggers.
又肥又淫荡 真是够恶心的
Fat and horny. It's fucking disgusting.
就算你有136千克 我依然想和你做爱的
If you were 300 pounds, I'd still do you.
真浪漫
So romantic.
- 我的儿子好吗 - 可没人说是男孩
- How's my boy? - Nobody said it's a boy.
我等不及想看你和他一起的样子
I can't wait to see the way you're gonna be with him.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我就是知道
I just know.
我能感觉到
I can sense it.
- 希望你是对的 - 宝贝 我是对的
- I hope you're right. - Baby, I am right.
美国海军在伊拉克阵亡人数
嗨 你爸联系过你了吗
Hey, did your dad get ahold of you?
我还没看我的电子邮件
I haven't checked my e-mails.
见鬼 你挂了以后就打给他好吗
Shit! Okay, you need to hang up and call him, all right?
- 为什么 怎么了 - 见鬼
- Why? What's wrong? - Fuck.
我太自私了 我都没想起来
I'm so selfish. I wasn't even thinking.
塔娅 怎么了 出什么事了
Taya, what's wrong? What happened?
你的弟弟也派遣了
Your little brother deployed.
什么意思 跳伞学校怎么了
What do you mean? What happened to jump school?
不 他没录取 你快挂了打给你爸
No, he didn't get in. You just hang up and call your dad, okay?
等等 什么意思 派遣到哪 他在哪
Wait. What do you mean? Deployed where? Where is he?
在那边
Over there.
他去伊拉克了
He's headed to Iraq.
对不起 亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey.
拿刀的那个人是约旦的武装分子
The man with the blade, he's a Jordanian militant.
本·拉登资助他 训练他
He's funded by Bin Laden. He's trained by Bin Laden.
他对本·拉登很忠诚
He is loyal to Bin Laden.
他叫扎卡维
His name is Zarqawi.
现在这个混蛋是
Now, this asshole is right
伊拉克基地组织的继承人
now the crown prince of Al-Qaeda in Iraq.
他的雇佣军 基地组织有五千人
His mercenary army, AQI, they're 5,000 strong.
现在 这些人可不是普通的小混混
Now, these guys are not your average shit-kickers.
这些家伙训练有素 报酬优厚
These guys are well trained, they are well paid.
而现在 继越战之后他们
And right now, they are
展开了最大的城市袭击
waging the largest urban assault since Vietnam.
扎卡维和他的副手 是我们的首要目标
Zarqawi and his lieutenants, these are our top priority.
现在只有一个办法可以将他们斩草除根
Now, there is only one way to root these guys out,
那就是挨家挨户地搜
and that is to go door to door, house to house,
直到找到他们
until we find them or we
或者找到愿意说出他们行踪的人
find someone who will give us their whereabouts.
所以我们需要每小时清查十幢房屋
So, we are going to need to clear 10 structures an hour,
我知道这数目很多 很激进
which, I know, is a lot. It's aggressive.
有空中支援我们才能稍稍放松
We're gonna be loosening things up with air support.
这是迄今我们最高优先的目标
This is the highest priority target we have to date.
这浑蛋要么死要么被抓 明白吗
I want this asshole dead or captured. Do you understand?
有没有问题
Are there any questions?
我要告诉你点事
I'll tell you something.
这些海军们一直横冲直撞
These marines keep rushing in like they're doing,
这会让他们没命的
they're gonna have their asses shot off.
他们是海军
Well, they're marines.
他们没有受过我们的训练
They don't get the training we do.
有一半的人半年前还是平民
Half these guys were civilians six months ago.
那就训练他们 让他们懂得团队协作
Well, let's coach them up. I'll show them how team guys do it.
我来带领街上的部队
I'll lead the unit on the street.
不能这样 你们需要你来掩护
No, can't do that. We need you on overwatch.
拜托 马克 如果我在街上 我就可以
Oh, come on. If I'm on the street, Marc, I could...
挨家挨户的搜查是这最危险的工作
House-to-house is the deadliest job here.
你是不是有救世主情结之类
You got some sort of savior complex?
不 我只是想打击坏蛋
No, I just want to get the bad guys.
但如果我看不到他们 我就无法击毙他们
But if I can't see them, I can't shoot them.
所有这些人 他们知道你的名字
Look, all these guys, they know your name.
有你掩护时他们觉得无敌
And they feel invincible with you up there.
- 不是 - 如果他们觉得他们就是无敌的
- They're not. - They are if they think they are.
为什么你不继续拿狙击枪了
Why don't you keep banging on the long gun?
让这些猎狗去找出扎卡维
We'll let these dogs sniff out Zarqawi.
你说基地组织有个狙击手参加过奥运会
You said AQI has a sniper in the Olympics,
但是伊拉克有三届比赛没晋级过了
but Iraq hasn't qualified a shooter in three games.
那是因为穆斯塔法不是伊拉克人
Well, that's 'cause Mustafa's not Iraqi.
他是叙利亚人
He's from Syria.
重整队伍
Regroup!
一旦你们进入了 我就看不到了
Hey, once you all gain entry, I can't see shit.
所以慢慢地靠近你们的目标
So take it slow and move through your target.
- 明白 - 小心手雷
- Understood. - Fire in the hole!
上 上 上
Go, go, go!
去他妈的
Fuck this.
我要去和陆战队一起清查房屋
I'm gonna go clear houses with marines.
- 你来不来 - 不 我不来
- You coming? - Fuck no, I'm not coming.
不 老兄 我惜命 我还想活着回家
No, man. I like my life. I'd actually like to make it home alive.
听着 他妈的去敲门
Look, it's not my job to
可不是我的工作 好吗
go fucking knocking down doors, all right?
那些人选错了工作 我才不会这么干
Those guys picked the wrong fucking job. I'm not doing that shit.
好吧 如果我在那没见到你
All right, well, if I don't see you down there,
你最好保证以后我也见不到你
you make sure I don't see you again.
嗨 介意我和你们一起吗
Hey. Y'all mind if I roll with you?
嘿 任何海豹突击队的人和我一起都好
Hey, man. Any SEAL is cool by me.
你是他们称之为传奇的那个人
You're that guy, the one they're calling The Legend.
你差不多确认干掉了二十四个人
You got like 24 confirmed kills.
- 谁会去数 - 真是个混蛋
- Well, who's counting? - That's fucking bad-ass.
我听说有些混蛋赶上来了
Yeah, I heard some motherfucker in Bravo's catching up, yo.
听着 我知道你们都不是吃素的
Listen. I know y'all are meat-eaters,
毫无疑问 但是我知道一些技巧
for sure, but I know a couple things,
我可以教你们些简单的
some simple shit I could show you.
也许能让我们活命 你们觉得如何
Maybe keep us above ground. What do you say?
- 好的 - 那行
- Yeah. - All right.
好极了
Right on.
- 兄弟 这是啥意思 - 破门手上
- Hey, what's that mean, bro? - Breacher up.
- 行动 - 趴下 趴在地上
- Moving. - Get down! Get down on the ground right now!
- 快趴下 - 别开枪 别开枪
- Get your fucking ass down! - No, no!
- 他听不懂英语 - 趴下
- He no understand! - Get down!
为什么在这 你应该
Why are you here? You're supposed
从这片区域撤走的 为什么还在这
to be evacuating this area. Why are you still here?
我是奥贝迪地区酋长
I am Sheikh Al-Obeidi.
什么酋长 你他妈的是谁
Sheik Alla-who?! Who the fuck are you?!
- 这儿是我家 我不走 - 老子管哪是你家
- This is my home! I stay! - I don't give a fuck it's your home!
先生 这里是战区 - 长官 求你了
This is a war zone, sir! - Sir, please!
让那小孩趴下 - 不要 不要
Get that kid down! - No! No!
长官 我可以帮你
You, sir. Let me help you.
我在后面的衣柜里发现了这些妇女
Found these bitches in the back closet.
欢迎你们来我家 你们都是贵客
You are welcome here. You are my guest.
你家还有多少人
How many more you have here?!
你让外面的士兵都进来
But tell the soldiers to come in.
别 这伊斯兰教徒想把我们都骗进来再炸个稀巴烂
No. This Hajji just wants us all in here so he can blow us up.
过去检查下他...
Go check his ass for a...
如果他看到美国人 就知道我们说过话
If he see American, he know we speak.
谁 谁看见你跟我们说话
Who? Who? Who saw you talking to us?
外面很危险 请让他们都进来
It's very dangerous. Please come in.
谁知道我们在跟你说话 谁 - 他来了 他来了
Who knows we're talking to you? Who?! - He come. He come.
他... 他来 他...
He... he come. He...
很坏 求你了
Very bad. Please.
- 这个目标安全吗 - 安全
- This target's secure? - Target secure.
带他们进来 头朝地
Bring them in. Get your head down on the ground.
双手放在背后
Put your hands behind your back.
快 快动起来
Now! Move now!
- 求你了 求你了 - 你说实话 我们就和你谈
- Please! Please! - You talk, we'll talk to you.
把他带到另一个房间
Bring him in the other room.
如果他和美国兵说话
If he talks to U.S. Soldiers,
他们就会来他家 把他们一家都杀掉
they will come to his house and make examples of them.
他 他是谁
He? Who's he? Who's he?
来这的人 人称屠夫
The man who comes, they call "The Butcher."
让人闻风丧胆
He's the despaired one.
他是魔鬼之子 撒旦之子
Son of Shaytan, son of... son of devil.
可以说他是个刽子手咯
Oh, he's like an enforcer?
对 他就是个刽子手
Yes, enforcer.
- 扎卡维的头号士兵 - 扎卡维
- Number-one soldier Zarqawi. - Zarqawi?
- 扎卡维 - 是的 我们想知道扎卡维在哪
- Zarqawi. - Yeah, we'd like to know where Zarqawi is.
你知不知道他在哪 告诉我们他现在何处
You know where he is? You tell us where he is right now.
我们怎么才能抓到他
How can we get him?
你有什么扎卡维的信息可以提供给我们 快说
Do you have information for us about Zarqawi? Tell us right now.
找到屠夫 就找到了扎卡维 他会向他报告
You find the Butcher, you find Zarqawi. He reports to him.
行 那我们要怎样找到他
Okay, well, how do we find him?
跟你说话时
All right, look at me when
要看着我 我们去哪找他
I'm talking to you. Where do we find him?
我们得了解寻找他们的风险 他要开口费
We must understand the risk to them, but he will ask for money.
- 十万美元 - 你要十万美元
- $100,000. - You need $100,000?
都没证实这个人到底存不存在
I have no proof this guy exists.
法蒂玛
Fatima!
您好
Howdy.
你好
Hello.
这就是证据
This is the proof.
行 听好 我想帮助你们
All right, look, I wanna help you out.
真的 但我需要一些东西
I do. But I need something.
我要电话号码 地址
I need phone numbers, address,
姓名 你得提供些什么
names. You have to give me something.
- 长官 第一排受制 - 开始行动
- Sir. First platoon's pinned down. - Let's move out!
酋长, 跟你说话时你要看着我
Sheikh, look at me when I'm talking to you.
喂 看着我 我需要些东西
Hey! Look at me! I need something.
我能帮你 酋长
I can help you out, Sheikh.
你给我个名字 我们就会处理掉他
You give me a name, and we will take care of it.
我向你保证 能让你们安全
I can promise you that. We will give you safety.
- 现在就告诉我 - 埃米尔·哈拉夫·弗努什
- Tell me right now! - Amir Khalaf Fanus!
- 是爱米尔·阿弗努什吗 - 是埃米尔·哈拉夫·弗努什
- Emile Anafanoos? - Amir Khalaf Fanus.
这个是屠夫的名字
This is the given name of the Butcher.
我们认为那个屠夫是扎卡维的二把手
We believe that the Butcher is Zarqawi's number two man.
这个就是你们要找的人
This is your guy right here.
没错 但你不知道他真名
Yeah, but you don't know his real name.
不然的话 你早就写上了
Otherwise, you'd have written it up there.
我们得到了他的几个化名
We got several aliases.
如果弗努什是真名的话...
Now, if "Fanus" is legit...
- 我们去见酋长 - 他要十万美元
- We'll... we'll go see the Sheikh. - He's asking for 100,000.
开价真不低 但如果他说出屠夫的下落 钱的事好说
Figures. But if he delivers the Butcher, he's gonna get it.
我是国防情报局的特工斯尼德
This is agent Snead, DIA.
我想查询埃米尔·哈拉夫·弗努什这个名字
I need a name check on an Amir Khalaf Fanus.
好的 我等着
Yeah, I'll wait.
如果我们要回去那 第三小队可以保驾护航
If we're gonna go back out there, team 3 can pull security.
不可能 如果我们要运钱的话
That's not gonna happen. Head shed's
上头会要求合约人也一起去
gonna want contractors on it if we're humping money.
恩 我在这 你掌握了什么
Yeah, I'm here. What do you got?
好的 行
All right. Okay.
我们去会会酋长
Let's go see the Sheikh.
轧死了只动物
Roadkill.
你知道屠夫是扎卡维的刽子手吗
You know the Butcher is Zarqawi's enforcer?
他们说他选的武器是只电钻
They say his weapon of choice is a fucking drill.
加入海军之前我去了神学院
Went to seminary school before I joined the Navy.
差点就当上牧师了
Was close to being a preacher.
那为什么没当上
And why didn't you?
我嗜赌
I love to gamble, man.
很爱掷骰子
Love those dice.
我喜欢这样的牧师
That's my kind of preacher.
现在打电话
It's like that now?
你还没听说过吧 我可是个传奇人物
Oh, haven't you heard? I'm The Legend.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, babe.
你说对了 医生说我怀的是男孩
You were right. The doctor says it's a boy.
什么
What?
是男孩
It's a boy!
是男孩啊
It's a boy?!
兄弟 恭喜你了
Hell, yeah, man. Congratulations!
克里斯
Chris?!
带上钱 去藏匿点
Grab the money! Get to the drop!
跑 快跑 带上包 带上包
Go! Go! Grab the bag! Grab the bag!
克里斯
Chris!
快跑 快跑 先离开这 回来再找他们算账
Go! Go! Get the fuck outta here! We'll come back for them.
宝贝
Baby?
- 我听到一声枪响 - 对
- I heard one shot. - Check.
成一个角度来的 离这300码远
Came in at an angle. Be 300 or more yards out.
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 你能看到他吗 - 我看到了个小窗户
- You got a bead on him? - I got a tiny little window.
操 我看到屠夫了
Shit! I got eyes on the Butcher.
他把酋长的儿子抓到大街上了
He's got the Sheikh's kid on the avenue.
请求快速反应部队支援
Requesting QRF.
我们在接近重要目标的过程中
We're being pinned down by
被狙击手牵制住了
sniper fire on approach of high value target.
坐标04536236 完毕
Grid 04536236. Over.
我放只烟雾弹
I wanna pop a smoke 'em and
保护这栋楼 我要去屋顶
secure this building. I'm going to the roof.
先别动
Hold up!
- 别动 - 我没动
- Hold. - Holding.
走
Go!
天啊 天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
敢和他们说话 那就跟他们一起死
放马过来 你个狗娘养的
Come on, you fucking son of a bitch!
去你妈的
Fuck you!
天啊 真是一团糟
Jesus Christ, what a fucking mess.
你就是个蠢货
You're one dumb son of a bitch,
你知道吗 你他妈在想什么
you know that? What the hell were you thinking?
你完全没保住战场
You completely failed to secure the battlefield.
调查期间我要把
I'm shutting this whole thing
所有的事都停了 回到基地去
down pending an inquiry. Get back to base!
我们要组建一个小队追击他
Hey, we gotta set up a squad and pursue him.
不用了 他们要我们停工
Nope, they're shutting us down.
什么意思
What do you mean?
没解决这事前不能离开前线
Can't leave the wire till they figure this shit out.
他不能就这样把我们丢下
Well, he can't just leave us like that.
我三周内就要回家了
Hey! I go home in three weeks!
老兄 看来三周会很漫长
Man, that's gonna be a long three weeks.
- 还好吗 - 怎么了 老爸
- How are you? - What's going on, pop?
宝贝
Hey, baby.
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- 我以为你死了 - 我不是好好的吗
- I thought you were dead. - Well, I'm right here.
不信你好好看看
Look at me.
- 你还好吧 - 恩
- You all right? - Yeah.
你是我迄今见过最美的人
You're the most beautiful thing I've ever seen.
我体内有个外星人在成长
I have an alien growing inside me.
而我卧室还有个陌生的男人
And there's a strange man in my bedroom.
应该说是我们的卧室
Well, it's our bedroom.
你的手感觉不一样了
Your hands feel different.
没变 他们... 还是我的手
Oh, no. They're... they're my hands.
- 为什么我这么紧张 - 我也是
- Why am I so fucking nervous? - Well, I am, too.
- 你才没有 你在撒谎 - 真的 我也很紧张 我发誓
- No, you're not. You're lying. - Yes, I am. I swear.
我怎么知道你肚子里的
How do I know some alien
外星人会不会跑出来把我抓走
in there is not gonna come out and grab me?
在午夜的时候
In the middle of the night.
那我就得...
Then I'm gonna have to...
把他闷死
choke him out.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
- 能保证吗 - 恩 当然
- Promise? - Yeah, of course.
你为什么对我这么好
Why're you so good with me?
宝贝 今天适合外出哦
Hey, babe. It might be nice to get out.
你在听我说话吗
You listening to me?
克里斯
Chris.
亲爱的 你今天想干嘛呢
What do you wanna do today, hon?
我原以为我们就在家放松放松
I thought we could just relax here.
好吧 就这样
Okay, we do that.
放松放松
Let's relax.
- 你在干什么呢 - 把脚放你身上啊
- What're you doing? - Putting my foot on you.
你知道 这真合我心意
Well, you know that's... that's the way to my heart.
那我就过来咯
I'm coming over.
宝宝看起来不错
And that looks great.
看 他在摸鼻子呢
Look. He's touching his nose.
- 你感觉怎样 - 我很好
- How are you feeling? - I'm all right.
我只想他快点离开我肚子 太累了
I just want him out. I'm tired.
- 临产期就在这几天了 - 希望如此
- Well, it's gonna be any day now. - I hope so.
你呢 凯尔先生 感觉如何
How 'bout you, Mr. Kyle? How're you feeling?
我感觉很好 谢谢你 医生
I'm feeling good. Thank you, ma'am.
我想消除压力很困难吧
I imagine it's hard to decompress.
也不是
Not really. No.
我们这是第一次离开家
This is the first time we've left the house.
能在家呆着我很开心
I'm happy to be home. Yeah.
来 带上这个 好吗
Here, put this on for me, would ya?
要是你想给我做点检查
I think if you wanna check anything out,
不如检查下我的膝盖
you may wanna check out these knees.
- 你抽烟吗 - 不抽 医生
- Are you a smoker? - No, ma'am.
- 喝酒吗 - 渴了才喝
- You drink? - Only when I'm thirsty.
血压测量数据是170/110
That's 170/110.
- 天啊克里斯 - 血压很高吗
- Jesus Christ, Chris. - Is that high?
如果你刚喝了十四杯咖啡就不算高
Not if you've just had 14 cups of coffee.
但对于一个坐着的人来说
But for someone who is sitting down...
我很感激你帮我检查 我会去看看的
Oh, I appreciate you... taking a look at that. I'll look into it.
- 谢谢 - 你真的会去看病吗
- Thank you. - Will you look into it?
当然
Yeah.
你刚才是故意拆我的台吧
You sabotaged me back there.
那不然我要怎么做 你一声不响的
What am I supposed to do? You're not talking.
表现得没事一样
You act like it's all okay.
- 一切都好 我很好 - 你才不好 克里斯 好吗
- It is okay. I'm fine. - You're not fine, Chris, all right?
你的血压高到了170/110 就好像...
Your blood pressure is, like, fucking 170/110. It's like...
我在高速公路上开车 阳光明媚 22度
I'm driving down the freeway. It's sunny. It's 72 degrees.
我很好 有战争正在进行 有人不断死去
I'm fine. There's a war going on. There's people dying.
甚至没有人讨论这个
No one's even talking about that.
就好像它没有发生过
It's like it's not even happening.
我们都依赖着手机
We're all on our cell phones,
过着简单而单纯的生活
living our simple, simplistic lives.
- 都没有新闻报道 没有人关心 - 克里斯
- It's not even on the news. No one cares. - Chris.
那儿正在打仗而我却要去购物中心
There's a war going on and I'm headed to the mall.
- 克里斯 我要生了 - 我不该在这里的
- Chris. It's happening. - I'm not supposed to be here.
- 怎么了 你还好吗 - 我要生了
- What's wrong? You okay? - It's happening.
糟了 好吧 我开回去
Shit. Okay. I'm gonna go back.
- 你他妈的疯了 你知道吗
- You're fucking crazy! You know that?
没事 嘿 亲爱的
It's okay. Hey! Baby, baby.
哦 我的天 亲爱的 - 你看上去真美
Oh, my God. Baby. - You look beautiful.
我他妈的要生了
It's fucking happening.
哦 我的宝贝
Oh, my baby.
看看你的妈妈
Look at your mama.
- 嘿 - 你好 宝贝
- Hey. - Hi, baby.
- 嘿 小伙子 - 嘿 宝贝
- Hey, little guy. - Hey, baby.
嘿 小伙子 看看我们做了什么
Hey, little guy. Look what we did.
看看我们做了什么 看看我们创造的
Look what we did. Look what we made.
看看我们所创造的
Look what we made.
宝宝在哭 我以为你会去抱他
The baby's crying. I thought you were gonna get him.
不 别麻烦关掉它了 我已经看到了
No, don't bother turning it off. I already watched it.
得确定下有没有
Had to make sure you didn't
伊拉克女朋友给你寄性爱录像
have an Iraqi girlfriend sending you sexy videos.
那是狙击手记录他所杀的人的录像 是穆斯塔法
That's a sniper recording his kills. That's Mustafa.
他在街上卖那鬼东西 他们是美国士兵
He sells that shit on the street. Those are American soldiers.
那天我们打电话的时候 是他吗 是吗
That day that we were on the phone, was that him? Was it?
克里斯 你就说说吧
Chris, just talk about it.
你不和我说并不是在保护我
You're not protecting me by not talking about it.
不 我不想你脑子里想着那个 你懂吗
No, I don't want you getting that in your head, ya understand?
好吧 我所想象的
Well, my imagination is so
比你能告诉我的更糟糕
much worse than anything you could tell me.
- 克里斯 - 宝贝 他们是该死的野蛮人
- Chris. - Babe, They're fucking savages.
不是关于他们
It's not about them.
是关于我们
It's about us.
什么
What?
你得让我们回到过去
You have to make it back to us.
好吗
Okay?
第二次派遣
欢迎回来 长官
Welcome home, chief.
琼斯上校在等我们 飞行愉快吗
Colonel Jones is waiting. How was the flight?
- 他妈的比圣诞节还漫长 -我想也是
- Damn longer than Christmas. - I bet.
- 嘿 能稍等一下吗 - 好的 快点啊
- Hey. Can you wait a second? - All right. Hurry up.
嘿 格伦特
Hey, Grunt!
- 克里斯 - 嘿 兄弟
- Chris? - Hey, brother!
嗨
Hi.
你还好吗  没缺胳膊少腿吧
You all right? You in one piece?
我听说你在外面被揍惨了
I heard you been kicking ass out here,
兄弟 他们所有人都这样说
man. All the guys, that's what they've been saying.
- 他们都这样说 - 对
- Yeah, that's what they say? - Yeah.
你怎么样 还好吗 他妈的真高兴见到你
How ya doing? You okay? Oh, shit, it's good to see you.
你是我的英雄 兄弟 好吗 你一直都是
You're my hero, bro. Okay? You always have been.
走吧 凯尔 上校在等我们
Let's go, Kyle! Colonel's waiting!
传奇人物
The Legend?
- 发生了什么 你还好吗 - 我会想念我的旅程的
- What happened? You all right? - Man, I'm gonna miss my ride.
嘿 发生了什么
Hey, what happened?
我只是很累 兄弟 我... 我要回家了
I'm just tired, man. I'm... I'm going home.
我为你而骄傲
I'm proud of you.
爸爸也一样 爸爸也为你而骄傲
Dad is, too. Dad's proud of you.
这地方真操蛋
Fuck this place.
- 你说什么 - 这地方真操蛋
- What'd you say? - Fuck this place.
长官 我们得走了 走吧
Chief, we got to move! Let's go!
- 你当长官了 恭喜啊 - 谢谢 长官
- You made chief. Congratulations. - Thank you, sir.
格恩斯基走了 好多高级军官都走了
Gronski's gone. A lot of the top brass are.
离开这里开始了新生活
Running off a new playbook now.
过去十年我一直在研究叛乱
I've studied insurgencies for the last decade.
我知道历史上的每一次战争
I know every stone thrown since before the first century.
这些战争是敌人心中的输与赢
These wars are won and lost in the minds of our enemy.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
那你知道这个吗
That you?
那是个十字军十字 长官
That's a crusader cross. Yes, sir.
对
Yeah.
你现在是伊拉克悬赏最高的人
You're now the most wanted man in Iraq.
你的人头价值十八万 恭喜啊
There's 180,000 on your head. Congrats.
别告诉我妻子 她也许现在就会去领赏的
Well, don't tell my wife. She might take that number right now.
我知道你想组成
I understand you wanna put
一个直接行动小组去搜寻屠夫
together a direct action squad to hunt the Butcher.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我们接到消息指明了他的活动区域
We got some Intel indicating his area of operations.
我要你让这些野蛮人懂得敬畏神明
I want you to put the fear of God into these savages...
找到他
and find his ass.
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
好的 我们去抓这混账东西
All right, let's go get this motherfucker.
走之前要做个突击测试
Gonna be a pop quiz before we leave.
- 下次少说点 大传奇 - 你说什么
- Small words next time, big legend. - What'd you say?
下次少说点
Small words next time.
你想听的话我可以告诉你那些故事
I'll tell you those stories if you want 'em.
- PPT做得真糟 - 谢谢 比格斯
- One hell of a PowerPoint, man. - Oh, thanks, Biggles.
总要有话要说 你个混账
Always gotta say something, motherfucker.
你的圣经 是防弹的吗
That Bible of yours, is that bulletproof?
什么 我放在这里的这本
What, the one I put in here?
我只是从没看你打开过它 我想
Yeah. I just... I never saw you open it. I assumed...
上帝 国家 家庭 对吗
God, country, family, right?
你有信仰吗
You got a God?
我有信仰吗 你越来越奇怪了
I got a God? You getting weird on me?
你要知道 在俄勒冈长大
You know, growing up in Oregon,
我们的房产周围有电围网
we had this electric fence around our property.
我们这些孩子抓着它看看谁坚持得最久
Us kids'd grab onto it and see who could hold on the longest.
战争有点类似这个
War feels kinda like that.
电流在你的骨头中
Puts lightning in your bones
让一切很难坚持下去
and makes it hard to hold on to anything else.
兄弟 你要对此袖手旁观吗
Hey, man, you need to sit this one out?
我只是想相信我们所做的
I just wanna believe in what we're doing here.
哦 那里有恶魔 我们看到过
Oh, there's evil here. We've seen it.
对 那里到处都有恶魔
Yeah. There's evil everywhere.
你想要这些混账东西
Oh, you want these
去到圣地亚哥或纽约吗
motherfuckers to come to San Diego or New York?
我们在保护的不止是这片垢土
We're protecting more than just this dirt.
好吧
All right.
我们去杀了这个混账
Let's go kill this fucker.
没错 就是这个建筑
Bingo. It's the building right here.
所有东边的房间都朝着饭店
Any apartment on the east side faces the restaurant.
进去 长官 快快快
Go in, sir. Go, go, go.
安全
Clear.
另一扇门
Other door.
- 好的 好的 - 立刻趴下
- Okay, okay. Okay. - Get down on the ground right now.
- 把手放在背后 - 好的
- Put your hands behind your back. - Okay.
目标安全
Target secure.
窗户交给我 克里斯
I got the window, Chris.
- 设置岗哨 兄弟 - 好的 我们去安排
- Set security, boys. - All right, let's get set up.
注意拐角
Corner.
把他们转移到其他房间
Let's move them into the other room.
你们问问他知不知道他 你认识他吗
Y'all ask if he knows him. You recognize this guy?
他说他不知道
He says he does not.
你呢 孩子 你认出他的脸吗
How 'bout you, son? You recognize this face?
你确定
You sure?
好吧 你一定要告诉他们
Well, you know, you make sure you
在我们走之前他们不能离开这
tell 'em they're not gonna go anywhere until we do.
嘿 你继续监视那扇窗户
Hey, you keep eyes on that window.
确保对每个进出的人都拍下照片
Make sure you take pictures of anybody coming and going.
发现了什么
What do we got?
- 十六个兵役年龄的男人进去了 - 十六个
- 16 military-aged males have gone in. - 16?
他们的客人比他妈的麦当劳的人还多
Yeah, they serve more customers than a fucking McDonald's.
这里 来看看这个
Here, check this out.
他还在里面吗
Is he still in there?
我盯着入口呢 他在里面
I clocked one point of entry. He's in there,
但是它不容易攻破
but it's not gonna be an easy breach.
哦 我不知道这个 兄弟
Oh, I don't know about that, man.
可能看到传奇 就让他进去了
Probably see The Legend and just let him right in,
你知道 一流的名人
you know, big-time celebrity.
叫他在他们的长袍上签名
Ask him to sign their burka.
参加他们孩子的生日聚会
Appear at their child's birthday parties.
你想怎样 我可没推销我自己
Hey, what is your problem? I didn't... I didn't promote myself.
对 你没有 混账 我是为你做的
Yeah, no shit, motherfucker. I did that for you.
要是没有我给你起那外号什么的
You would never made chief if I
你绝对当不了长官
hadn't nicknamed you the fucking myth or some shit.
他邀请你去参加古尔邦节晚餐
He invites you to join him for an Eid Al Adha supper.
他说 "那天 每个人都能来做客"
He says, "On this day, everyone has a seat at my table."
哦 他真慷慨
Oh, that's pretty generous of him.
那可真接近啊 兄弟
That was, like, close, man.
拿根黄瓜 把黄瓜放进桶里再加点醋
Take a cucumber. Take cucumber and put it in a tub with vinegar.
放些辣椒和一个柠檬进去 泡一晚上
Stick in cayenne pepper and a lemon... and let it soak overnight.
就这样 再加点伏特加
It's that, and just add vodka.
我的主意 你们想参入吗
That's the idea. You wanna get in on it?
来就来 老兄 我是地下投资者
Let's do it, dude. I'm a ground-floor investor.
比格斯 你从没做过一天饭
Biggles, you never cooked a day in your life.
老兄 那才是真正的问题
Dude, that was the real question.
那非常现实
That was super real.
随便一个人都比我们厉害
All these random people getting behind us.
哦 我的天 我落在传奇后面了
Oh, my God, I fell in behind the myth.
天呐
Holy shit.
- 拜托 兄弟 用点脑子 - 我去洗个手
- Come on, man. Get some brains. - I gotta wash my hands.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey!
- 去看看那个 - 留在这里 留在这
- Go check that out. - Stay right here. Stay here.
- 嘿 搞什么 - 比格斯 帮我一下
- Hey, what the fuck?! - Biggles, help me out.
看到了吗 穆斯林
See that, Muj?
你看到吗
You see that?
- 他妈的怎么了 -把翻译带进来
- What the fuck's going on? - Bring the terp in.
哦 惨了
Oh, shit.
好的 现在你告诉他
All right. Now you tell
他要被送去拘留
him that he's gonna be sent off to detention
伊拉克法庭会决定怎么处置他
and the Iraqi courts can decide what to do with him.
或者他可以帮我们进入楼下的饭店
Or he can help us get inside of that restaurant downstairs.
你告诉他 说那是他的选择
You tell him. Say it's his choice.
就是这
That's it.
解除警报
All clear.
好 好 行动
Good, good. Moving.
突击队就绪
Assault team set.
- 进入紧张状态 安全准备就绪 - 目标正在移动
- We're in tight. Security set. - Package is moving.
还有十五米
15 meters out.
十米
10 meters.
五米
5 meters.
他在敲门
He's knocking.
等等
Hold.
他们在审合他
They're vetting him.
就寝时间到了 穆斯林
Lights out, Muj.
就地处死 就地处死
Execute. Execute.
扔手榴弹 扔手榴弹
Frag out! Frag out!
- 比格斯 后面有人出来吗 - 没 没有动静
- Biggles, anything coming out the back? - Negative. No movement.
哦 他妈的
Oh, shit.
- "迪," 把他放下来 - 好的
- "D," Take him down. - Got him.
干掉他
Get him down.
哦 惨了
Oh, shit!
我们发现一个地道 注意后面 睁大眼睛
We found a tunnel. Watch your back. Keep your eyes open.
遭遇 遭遇
Contact! Contact!
遭遇 后退
Contact! Drop back!
突击方向那边 突击方向那边有人扛着榴弹炮
White-side! RPG on the white-side!
屠夫要逃了
Butcher's on the move.
重复 屠夫要逃了 我正在追
Repeat, Butcher's on the move. I'm in pursuit.
屠夫已击毙 各就各位
Butcher's down. Move in your position.
我的意思是 我提出给他拘留保护 要不要取决于他
I mean, I offered him detention. It was his choice.
他做出了错误的选择 所以如此 战争的迷雾
Picked the wrong side. It's all there is to it. Fog of war.
克里斯 别管了 我们走 黄花菜都凉了
Yo, Chris! Fuck it, man. Let's go. Shit's getting hairy.
长官 有武装叛乱分子正朝
Sir, we have armed insurgents
这个方向来 我们得赶紧离开
moving this way. We need to make tracks.
头儿 那边可有得忙了
Heck of a job there, chief.
- 你还要一个 还是你已经够了 - 看 这是什么
- You want another one, or are you good? - Look. What is this?
不 它吐出什么你就拿什么 这东西就是这样设计的
No. Well, you get what it gives you. That's how this thing works.
你拿不到那个 如果你就想要那个的话
You don't get that one, if that's the one you want.
我喜欢那个
I like that.
那个不错 那个挺强力的
That's good. That's strong.
- 克里斯·凯尔 过来 你的卡车已经好了
- Chris Kyle, come on. Your truck's ready.
你想扭多少次都行
You can move that all you want.
你的卡车好了 不可能
Your truck's ready. Im... impossible.
- 给我你的信用卡 - 好的 有意思
- Give me your credit card. - Okay. Interesting.
- 我想我已经给过你了 - 噢 对
- I already gave it to ya, I think. - Oh, right.
什么 嘿 把那个捡起来
What? Hey, just pick that up off the floor.
确保你把它们全都捡起来 这里还有一个
Make sure you get all of them up. Well, you got one back here.
打扰下 先生
Excuse me, sir?
- 你是克里斯·凯尔长官吗 - 是的 先生
- Are you chief Chris Kyle? - Yes, sir.
我叫德斯 我们在费卢杰见过面 你救了我的命
My name is Mads. We met in Fallujah. You saved my life.
- 我救了 - 是的 先生
- I did? - Yes, sir.
我们被困在一间房里直到你和第一师进来
We were stuck in a house until you came in with the 1st marines.
是你把我扛出去的
You were the one that carried me out.
海军陆战队也救过我们不少次
Oh, wow. Well, the marines saved our ass plenty of times.
- 你怎样 还好吗 还能坚持吗 - 我很好 嗯
- How are you? You all right? You holding up? - Great. Yeah.
我只是很感激我还活着 但是
I'm... I'm just grateful to be alive. It hasn't been...
腿被击中 这并非易事
Colt. It hasn't been easy.
嗯 你瞧
Well, you know.
很多人失去的可不仅是一条腿
A lot of guys lost more than just a leg.
你失去了什么朋友吗
Did you lose some friends?
嗯 当然有 但是我说的是那些活着的人
Well, that, too. But I'm talking 'bout the guys that lived.
他们活着回来了 但是他们只是
That made it back, but they're just not...
他们的心没回来 你懂吗
they're just not back, you know?
- 他们似乎无法恢复正常 - 是啊
- They can't seem to get right. - Yeah.
不如你来一下退伍军人事务部吧
Why don't you come down to the V.A.
有时间的话 那的人会非常高兴的
Sometime? The guys would love it.
他们都知道传奇人物是谁
They all know who The Legend is.
- 那听起来是个好主意 - 嘿 伙计
- Yeah, that sounds like a good idea. - Hey, buddy.
我能告诉你些事么
Can I tell you something?
你老爹 他是个英雄
Your dad? He's a hero.
是的 他救过我的命 他还...
That's right. He saved my life, and he...
他还帮我回到了我的小天使身边
he helped me get back to my little girl.
- 所以 谢谢你把他借给我们 - 好唔
- So, thank you for lending him to us. - Okay.
没有他我就不会在这里
I wouldn't be here without him.
我的家人感谢你的帮助
My family thanks you for your service.
谢谢 照顾好自己
Okay, thank you. All right. Take care of yourself.
- 能再次见到你真好 - 好的
- It's great to see you again. - All right.
- 有时间来下退伍兵事务所吧 - 好的
- Come down to the V.A. Sometime. - Okay. Yeah.
把你的小蜥蜴玩具拿上
Grab your little lizard up there.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 不客气 - 祝一天愉快
- You're welcome. - Have a good day.
- 也祝你愉快 - 好的
- You have a good day. - Okay.
好了 让我们去见你妹妹吧 兄弟
All right, let's go meet your sister, bubba.
嘿 这需要帮助 我女儿在哭
Hey. Some help here? My daughter's crying.
我的女儿在那 我想她在哭
That's my daughter over there. I think she's crying.
能请你过去一下吗 不好意思
Can you help tend to her, please? Excuse me.
嘿 嘿 你要去哪
Hey! Hey, where you going?
嘿
Hey!
嘿 能请你去看一下我女儿吗
Hey, will you tend to my daughter, please?
嘿
Hey!
嘿 看下我女儿 马上
Hey! Tend to my daughter, please! Right now!
我自己编织回忆
I'm making memories by myself.
无可与我分享之人
I have no one to share them with.
我们有一辈子来做那些呢
Yeah, well, we got our whole lives for that.
那样的生活何时开始
When does that start?
甚至你人处此地 心却不在
Even when you're here, you're not here.
我看得到你 感觉得到你
I see you. I feel you.
但是你的心却不在这里
But you're not here.
我因此而恨你的小队
I hate the teams for it.
我真的恨
I do.
你是我的丈夫
You're my husband.
你是我孩子的父亲
You're the father of my children,
但是他们是把你拉你回去的人
but they're the ones that pull you back.
但是 他们不能等 我们可以
Yeah, but, you see, they... they can't wait, and we can.
如果你认为这战争没有改变你 就错了
If you think this war isn't changing you, you're wrong.
你只能暂时的压制战火而已
You can only circle the flame so long.
那是事实
It's true.
卡迪拉克31 指挥官
Cadillac 31 actual,
我们目前在马里兰街
we're tailing the Butcher's
跟踪屠夫的情报员 完毕
courier currently on Maryland street. Over.
嘿 买到戒指了
Hey! Got the ring.
从哪 从这
From where? From here?
对 他妈这便宜多了
Yeah, man. Fuck, yeah. It's so much cheaper here.
伙计 你从那些野蛮人手里买的吗
Dude, you bought it from savages?
你怎么知道这钻石不沾血
How do you know it's not a blood diamond?
你他妈的还在乎这些 老兄
Oh, what the fuck do you care, man?
你已经让那血流成河了 你是传奇啊
You've spilled so much blood over here. You're The Legend.
那可不是为了块石头
Oh, that's not for a rock.
无所谓了
What the fuck ever, man.
那可真虚伪
That's just hypocritical.
别这么咄咄逼人 不 别离得太近
Hey, ease up on that. No, don't get too close.
- 好的 我知道
- All right. Hey, I know.
你告诉她你从哪买的了吗
Did you tell her where you bought it from?
扎莱什 美国老牌珠宝店
当然没 我会告诉她那戒指是从扎莱什那买的
Fuck no. I'm gonna tell her I got that shit from Zales.
你还在吧 伙计
Hey, you still with us, cookie?
就在你后面半个街区 宝贝 我们前戏已经做完了 比格斯
Just a half block back, baby. We are wet and ready, big giggles.
你知道么 迪
You know, "D"...
我预言20年后我们会重逢
I predict in 20 years, we're gonna have a reunion...
然后你会嫁个汉子
and you'll be married to a dude.
只要你会做饭和搞卫生
As long as you cook and clean.
- 看 他们在那 - 见鬼
- Now, there they are. - Oh, shit.
穆斯塔法把他的眼线放出来了
Mustafa's got his peepers out.
Keyser Soze是电影《普通嫌疑犯》中罪犯使出障眼法所虚构的幕后黑手
这混蛋太会伪装了 伙计
This motherfucker is Keyser fucking Soze, bro.
嘿 下次你有机会时
Hey, next time you get a clear shot,
试着别再打偏了 行吧
you try not to miss him, all right?
要不是得救你的命
Well, I would've gotten him in
我已经在胡同里打死他了
the alleyway if I didn't have to save your ass.
所以你要当我的伴郎么
So you gonna be my best man?
就我一个 还是其他人一起啊
Oh, just me? Or is it gonna be everybody else, too?
老兄 伴郎只会有一个
There's only gonna be one best man, dude.
一号车正在交火
Vehicle 1 taking fire.
- 行行好 给我打中一个 - 好的
- Come on, give me a shot. - All right.
比格斯 走
Biggles, move.
安全
Clear.
跟我来一个
One on me.
我们抓到他了
We got him.
车辆安全了
Vehicle is secure.
设置岗哨 克里斯
Set security, Chris.
没危险
Nope.
屋顶安全
Rooftop secure.
你不担心她把那个拿去扎莱什么
Aren't you worried that she's gonna take that thing to Zales,
看看你到底花了多少钱
find out how much you spent?
- 不 我不担心 - 设置岗哨
- Well, no, I wasn't. - Set security.
- 现在我有点担心了 - 你应该担心
- Now I'm a little worried about it. - You should be.
你的意思是 她能追查这钻石到扎莱什那
What do you mean, she can trace the diamond to Zales?
我不认为那会...
I don't think that's gonna...
你还好吗 兄弟 你没事的
You okay, buddy? You're all right.
有人负伤 比格斯负伤 西北角 屋顶
Got a man down. Biggles is down. Northwest corner, rooftop!
坚持住 伙计
Hang in there, bud.
需要一个医疗兵 立刻
I need a corpsman right now!
兄弟 我们扶你起来然后带你下楼
Okay, bubba. We're gonna pick you up and take you downstairs.
我能走
I can walk.
让他进悍马 让他进悍马
Get him in the Humvee. Get him in the Humvee.
暂停一下
Breaking off.
我扶住他了 我扶住他了
I got him. I got him.
- 快 进来 坚持住 比格斯 - 草
- Come on. Get in. Hang in there, Biggles. - Fuck.
坚持住 比格斯
Hang in there, Biggles.
坚持 比格斯
Hang in, Biggles.
- 没事的 - 我很抱歉
- It's okay. - Shit, I'm sorry, man.
抱什么歉 你抱什么歉
For what? What are you sorry for?
去那个屋顶是我的错
It's my fault we went on that roof.
我会死吗
Am I gonna die?
妈不会 比格斯 你他妈的是海豹突击队
Fuck no, Biggles. You're a fucking frogman.
突击队的人他妈的不会死
Frogmen don't fucking die.
在这该死的伤口上撒点沙子
Gonna put some sand in this fucking cut.
我们再他妈给你一壶水
We'll get you a fucking canteen of water.
你就好了 比格斯 坚持住
You're gonna be fucking fine, Biggles. Hang in there.
克里斯 你保证她会拿到那戒指 好吗
Hey, Chris. You make sure she gets that ring, all right?
我保证
Sure will.
好了 吸液器慢点 递我下牵引器
All right, let's decrease suction. The retractor, please.
再拿点血袋 还要多久才能给他照X光
More blood. How long before we get film on him?
还需要一个单位的血 再给我三小时
We need another unit of blood. Give me a 3 hrs only.
- 好的 生理盐水...马上 - 吸液器开大点
- All right, saline... now. - More suction.
- 把你的手放在这 - 好
- Hold your hands right here. - Okay.
交差配血试验 现在就要那些数据
Type and cross. I need those numbers now.
你看到那子弹从哪来的了吗
Did you see where it came from?
看到了 在1000米之外
Yeah, it was more than 1,000 meters out.
敌方狙击手中只有一个能做到
Only one enemy sniper coulda made that shot.
他能挺下来吗
Will he make it?
得看这轮治疗结束如何 要48小时
Took a round off the feed tray cover. Was 48.
看起来不妙
Doesn't look good.
这是第一个中弹的海豹突击队员 长官
That's the first SEAL hit, sir.
操他妈的
Fuck!
什叶派的线人 一个出租车司机
Shi'a cab driver we source
说有个要塞就在距离那七户远的地方
is saying there's a stronghold seven doors down.
掩护你们撤退的海军部队还在那交战
Marine units covered your exfil are still engaged there.
我能理解如果你
I can understand if you
想退出重组小队的话 一切取决于你
want to stand down and regroup. It's up to you.
依据复仇原则
Lex talionis.
以眼还眼
Eye for an eye.
我们这就回去
We're going back out.
- 他妈的棒极了 - 草 这就对了
- Fucking "A." - Fuck, yes.
我们走
Let's go.
好戏开场
It's on.
还有两公里远
Two klicks out.
走廊安全
Hallway clear.
往左边 注意
On the left. Bumping.
走廊
Hallway.
走廊安全 向左走
Hallway clear. On the left.
安全
Clear.
解除警报
All clear.
马克 看上去有人走得很仓促
Hey, Marc. Looks like someone left in a hurry.
- 有人倒下 - 掩护窗口
- Man down! - Cover the window!
有人中弹
Man down!
- 封锁窗户 - 封锁窗户
- Cut that window! - Cut that window!
别这样 马克
Come on, Marc.
走 兄弟 我抓住你了
Let's go, buddy. I got you,
我抓住你了 看着我 看着我
man. I got you. Look at me. Look at me.
我抓住你了
I got you.
马克死了 兄弟
Marc's gone, bro.
有个海豹突击队员倒下 装甲车立即回来
I got one SEAL down. I need cabs back immediately.
我们要他妈的把他运走
We gotta fucking move him.
荣耀是某些人所追求的
"Glory is something some men chase,
而对于那些倒在血泊中的战士
"And others find themselves stumbling upon
一切荣誉皆是虚无
"Not expecting to find it.
无论如何 是一种高尚的行为
"Either way, it is a noble gesture that one...
将荣誉授予这些烈士
"Finds bestowed upon them.
我的问题是 从何时开始
"My question is, when does
光荣逐渐消失而成为了不正当的侵略
glory fade away and become a wrongful crusade?
或是藉由不正当的手段 将活生生的生命
"Or an unjustified means by which consumes one...
吞噬殆尽 我已经
"Completely? I've...
见过太多战争
"Seen war...
我也见过太多的死亡
"And I've seen... death."
准备 立正
Detail. Ten-hut!
举枪
Port arms!
准备
Ready!
瞄准
Aim.
射击
Fire!
准备
Ready.
瞄准
Aim.
射击
Fire!
准备
Ready.
瞄准 射击
Aim. Fire!
举枪敬礼
Present arms!
马克两周前写了那封悼念词
Marc wrote that letter two weeks ago.
他有没有告诉过你
Did he say any of that to you?
克里斯 我想知道你对他的悼念词有什么感想
Chris, I wanna know what you thought of his letter.
一个基地组织的线人提供了一条线索
An AQI informant had called in a tip,
当时比格斯中枪了
and... Biggles had just been shot.
我们被情绪冲昏了头脑
We were operating out of emotion,
自投罗网 中了敌人的埋伏
and we just walked right into an ambush.
但这并没有杀死他
But that's not what killed him.
是那封信 那封信杀死了马克
That letter did. That letter killed Marc.
他就这样放弃了 付出了生命的代价
He just... he let go, and he paid the price for it.
在这里签字
Sign in here?
嗨 老兄
Hey, buddy.
- 嗨 克里斯 - 是的
- Hey, Chris? - Yeah.
- 你在哪呢 老兄 - 我在这 我在这
- Where you at, man? - I'm right here. I'm right here.
- 该死 你怎么瞎成这样了 - 是啊 都他妈炸的
- Shit, you're blind as a bat. - Yeah, it fucking blows.
- 但是他们说会修复我的脸 - 哦 感谢上帝
- They say they're gonna fix my face, though. - Oh, thank God.
- 也是时候了 你的脸的确需要修补一下 - 太早了 老兄
- About time. Your face needs some fixing. - It's too soon, man.
- 还早吗 - 早得很了
- It is too soon? - Way too soon.
- 嗨 我听说你求婚了 - 是啊
- Hey, I heard you proposed. - Yeah.
好样的
Well, good for you.
你没有告诉她那枚钻戒是从
You didn't tell her you bought that diamond...
- 你告诉她你是在扎莱什买的 对吧 - 没有
- you told her you bought it at Zales, right? - No.
- 你没告诉她 - 不 不 买了个新的
- You didn't? - No. No, got a new one.
比原来的小一点 她爸爸帮我挑的
It's a smaller one. Her dad helped me out with it.
- 哦 不错 - 是啊
- Oh, nice. - Yeah.
很好
Oh, good.
她不肯离开我 老兄
She wouldn't leave me, bro.
我让她离开我 但她不肯
I told her to go, and she wouldn't leave.
这样对她不公平
She's getting a raw fucking deal.
你为什么要这么说 别这么说 她还有你啊
Why would you say that? Don't say that. She's got you.
- 还有你五厘米的小丁丁 - 五厘米吗
- All two inches of you. - Two inches.
我很庆幸这事发生在我身上 而不是你
Yeah, you know, I'm glad this happened to me and not you.
你根本无法接受这种事情
Ain't no way you coulda handled it.
你也许是对的
Yeah, you're probably right.
他们说你是美国军事史上最致命的狙击手
So they say you're the deadliest sniper in U.S. Military history.
- 是这样吗 - 我是这么听说的
- Oh, is that right? - That's what I heard.
- 敌人逃到了萨德尔市 - 你不是要回战场吧
- The bad guys ended up in Sadr City. - You're not going back.
是的 我们要回去 将他们一网打尽
Yeah, we are. We're gonna wall 'em in and hunt 'em down.
别这样 老兄 你不必如此
Nah, come on, man. You don't have to do that.
我们必须要这么做 你是我的兄弟
Oh, we have to do that. You're my brother.
我要让他们为此付出代价
And they're gonna fucking pay for what they did to you.
呼呀 传奇
Hooyah, Legend.
谢谢你
Fucking hooyah.
如果我有什么不测 你要好好的
Something happens to me, you'd be all right.
找另一个更好的人
You'd find someone else.
你想死吗
Do you wanna die?
是不是这样
Is that what it is?
不
No.
那就告诉我
Then just tell me.
告诉我你为什么要这么做
Tell me why you do it.
- 拜托 - 我想知道你的想法
- Oh, come on. - I wanna understand.
宝贝 我是为了你 你知道的 我要保护你
Babe, I do it for you. You know that. I do it to protect you.
- 不 你不是 - 我是
- No, you don't. - Yes, I do.
我在这里
I'm here.
你的家人在这里 你的孩子根本没有父亲
Your family is here. Your children have no father.
我必须要效忠于我的国家
Well, I have to serve my country.
这些全他妈是狗屁
That is such fucking bullshit!
- 不是 - 你不知道什么时候该退出
- No, it's not. - You don't know when to quit.
你已经尽了你的职责 我们牺牲够多了
You did your part. We've sacrificed enough.
你让别人去上战场
You let somebody else go.
- 让别人上战场 - 是的
- Let somebody else go? - Yeah.
- 我的良心会受到谴责 - 那就想办法克服
- I couldn't live with myself. - Yeah, well, you find a way.
你一定要
You have to.
好吧 我要你变回一个有血有肉的人
Okay, I need you to be human again.
我需要你在这里
I need you here.
亲爱的 我需要你在这里
Baby, I need you here.
如果你再弃我们而去
If you leave again...
你回来的时候 我们不会在这里等你
I don't think we'll be here when you get back.
过来
Come here.
第四次派遣
克里斯
Chris.
我们已经连续三晚受到攻击了 老兄
We've been shot off position three nights in a row, man.
费卢杰很糟糕 拉马迪更糟糕
Fallujah was bad. Ramadi was worse.
这简直像是圣经里的场景 克里斯
This shit is fucking biblical, Chris.
还有谁是来给兄弟报仇的吗
Is there any other punishers here?
松鼠退了 多贝本来要来的
Squirrel cycled out. And Dauber was coming back,
但他老婆死活也不让他过来
but his wife knocked him up.
如果我再带一条毯子回家的话
And if I bring home another rug,
我老婆会杀了我的 克里斯
my wife'll murder my motherfucking ass, Chris.
- 兄弟义气什么的 对吧 - 兄弟义气
- Teams and shit, right? - Teams and shit.
老兄 比格斯的事真是让人难过
Man, that Biggles news hit hard, man.
我走之前去医院看过他
I went to see him in the hospital before I left.
那混蛋瞎了
Motherfucker can't see shit.
比格斯死了 克里斯
Biggles is gone, Chris.
昨天他做手术 他死在了手术台上
He was in surgery yesterday, and... he died on that table.
嗨 我是塔娅 现在无法接电话
Hey, this is Taya. I can't get to the phone,
请留言
so please leave a message.
是我 我只想听听你的声音
It's me... Just calling to hear your voice.
我很想你们 我一直在考虑你说的
I'm missing you guys. Been thinking about some things you said.
告诉孩子们我爱他们 我也爱你
Tell the kids I love 'em. I love you, too.
不要捡
Don't pick it up.
他妈的不要捡
Don't you fucking pick it up.
小兔崽子
Son of a bitch.
快他妈扔了
Fucking drop it.
扔掉啊 你个小杂种
Drop it, you little cocksucker.
好了 听好了 上面认为
All right, listen up. The head-shed
丁字墙可以困住基地组织的余党
believe this T-wall here will help win the war
让我们打赢这场战争
by trapping remaining AQI behind it.
问题是有一个狙击手从远处
Problem is the engineers building the goddamn things
一个接一个地
are getting picked off by
射杀了建造丁字墙的工程师
one single sniper from deep behind the wall.
有多远
How deep?
- 大概一千米 - 是不是穆斯塔法
- Roughly 1,000 meters. - Is it Mustafa?
- 谁 - 我不知道 老兄
- Mu-who? - I don't know, dude.
就是那个杀了我们的朋友比格斯的混蛋 老兄
The sniper who killed our fucking friend Biggles, man.
不管这个混蛋是谁
He can be whoever the fuck
随你们怎么说 我们只要他死
you need him to be. We just need him dead.
你们会被送到敌人领地北面 相距六个街区
We'll shuttle you six blocks north into enemy territory,
在他开枪的时候
which will put you right up under
你们会直接处于他的面前
the sniper's nose when he takes his shot, okay?
在这种沙尘暴天气吗
In the middle of a fucking sandstorm?
带上你的护目镜 小鹿
Bring your fucking goggles, Bambi.
我们要击毙这个狙击手 明白吗 做好准备
We need to shut this shooter down. Understood? Gear up.
- 是 长官 - 是 长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
安全 开始行动
It's clear. Move out.
安全
Clear.
- 我们机动 你掩护 - 好
- We're maneuver. You're base. - Yep.
走
Go.
Go!
- 安全 - 前进
- Clear. - Moving.
走 走
Go! Go!
全部安全
All clear.
设置岗哨
Set security.
街上有人在移动 不要射击
The streets are crawling. Hold your fire.
这鬼地方全他妈是沙子
Enter the fucking sandman.
- 有人倒下 - 有人倒下
- Man down! - Man back!
操
Shit!
射击来自东面
Shot came from the east!
该死的我们搞错了方向
We set up in the wrong fucking direction.
别管他 不要射击 我们正下方有敌人
Doesn't matter. Hold your fire. We got uglies right below us.
发现情况 距离1900码[1737米]
I got something 1,900 yards out.
操 这么远根本看不见
Fuck, you can't even see that far out.
不要射击 你会暴露我们的
Hold your fire. You'll expose us all.
他是对的 传奇 这样不好
He's right, Legend. No bueno.
更正 距离是1920米
Correction. It's 2,100 yards out.
那已经超过一英里了 不可能击中的 克里斯
That's more than a mile. Impossible shot, Chris.
是他
It's him.
这里是"拳击手"任务分队
This is task unit bruiser.
已经锁定目标 启动快速反应部队 完毕
I got eyes on target. Initiate QRF. Over.
收到 快速反应部队将在美国东部时间二十分钟内赶到
Copy that. ET on quick reaction force is 20 minutes out.
- 他锁定了我们的人 - 你确定是他吗
- He has eyes on our guys. - Can you confirm it's him?
是他
It's him.
- 是他 - 你决定吧 克里斯
- Oh, it's him. - It's your call, Chris.
快速反应部队二十分钟赶到
Quick reaction force is 20 minutes out.
你他妈不准射击
You'll stand the fuck down!
你要是有把握 就开枪吧 老兄
If you got it, take it, man.
目标越小 偏差越小
Aim small, miss small.
为了比格斯
Do it for Biggles.
你把我们害惨了 神枪手
You just fucked us, Legend.
目标倒下
Tango down.
立刻派遣快速反应部队支援
We need QRF asap!
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
他锁定了我们的人
He had eyes on our guys.
- 我就解决了他 - 是啊
- And I took him out. - Yeah.
现在我们就像砧板上的鱼
Now we're fucked like a football bat.
比格斯会为你骄傲的
Biggles would be proud.
你做到了 克里斯
You did it, Chris.
E7K 警告
Echo 7 kilo, be advised you
敌人正在从各个方向包围你们的位置
have enemy approaching all directions of your pos.
敌人在突击方向 该死的传奇 操
White-side! Goddamn it, Legend. Fuck!
好吧 我们走 快点
Yeah, let's go. Come on.
好吧 有两条路可以到达屋顶
All right, I see two ways up onto the roof.
我们要将它们全部封锁
We wanna lock both staircases.
节约弹药
Conserve ammo.
吃枪子儿吧 混账东西
Get some, motherfuckers.
E7K 你们右侧方发现重型炮弹
Echo 7 kilo, you have tango-heavy gun on your green-side.
我们受到强火力攻击
We're taking effective fire,
突击方向 火力很强 突击方向
white-side! Effective fire, white-side!
迪 我只剩两个弹匣了 我们得出去
"D", I'm down to two mags! We gotta move!
不要停止射击 老兄
Don't stop fucking shooting, man!
快速反应部队距离我们三个街区
QRF's stuck three blocks out.
- 我没子弹了 - 三点方向 装上最后一个弹匣
- I'm out! - 3 o'clock. Loading last mag.
我只剩一个弹匣了
I've only got one mag left!
弹药用尽 弹药用尽 谁有多余的弹匣
I'm black! I'm black! Anybody got a mag?!
我们坚持不下去了 我们要离开这里
We can't hold 'em any longer! We gotta move!
这些家伙简直就是活靶子
Those guys are sitting ducks.
- 我不想在街上拖走 - 这就对了 干吧
- I don't wanna get dragged in the street. - That's it. Do it.
呼叫支援
Call it in.
这里是R2B 请求军械空投
This is Rio 2 Bravo requesting ordnance drop.
- 坐标号码04837959 - 你们和目标位置相同
- Grid number 04837959. - That target location is your position.
我他妈当然知道这是我的位置
I know my fucking position!
他们就在我们正上方 赶紧扔
They're right on top of us. Just drop it!
毒蛇34 移动到最终攻击航向
Viper 34, move to final attack heading.
这是毒蛇 34 收到 三十秒准备
Viper 34. Roger. 30 seconds out.
喂
Hello?
宝贝儿
Baby?
克里斯 宝贝 我听不清楚 喂
Chris? Baby, I ca... baby, I can't hear you. Hello?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
- 我准备好回家了 - 什么
- I'm ready to come home. - What?
我看见目标建筑了
I have the building in sight.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
我准备好要回家了 宝贝儿
I'm ready to come home, baby.
克里斯
Chris?
这里视野很差 我停留不了多久
It's pretty bad air up here. I can't hold this much longer.
告诉飞行员 投弹
Tell the pilot "Turn it loose."
毒蛇 34 攻击
Viper 34. Fire away.
没击中
Target missed.
他妈的
Shit.
我们必须马上撤 走 行动
We need to exfil now! Let's go! Let's move!
我们撤
We gotta move!
E7K 可以从右侧方撤退
Echo 7 kilo, green-side is clear for exit.
我出来了 我正朝右侧的滑杆方向走
I got the out. Green-side pole on my go!
他们在屋顶上
They're on the roof.
我们走
Let's go!
最后一个
Last man!
去后面
Get to the back!
走 快走
Go! Go! Go!
来 进来 进来
Come on! Inside, inside!
上车 赶快上车 赶紧撤
Get in the truck! Get in the truck now! We got to go!
快来 我们必须赶快撤
Come on! We got to get out now!
拉我一把
Let me up.
来 拉我一把
Come on, let me up. Come on.
克里斯呢
Where's Chris?
他刚才还在我后面 兄弟 克里斯来了吗
He was just behind me. Where is Chris, man?
把门打开
Open the fucking door.
不要开车
Stop the goddamn rig!
他在哪儿 克里斯
Where is he?! Chris!
克里斯 快来
Chris, come on!
- 快来 - 你他妈把车停住
- Come on! - Hold the fucking vehicle, man!
我们不会扔下你的 来啊 克里斯 抓住我的手 快 克里斯
We can't leave you! Come on, Chris! Grab my hand! Come on, Chris!
把他拉进来
Pull him in now!
快上来 克里斯
Come on, Chris!
- 喂 - 嘿 是我
- Yeah? - Hey, it's me.
我刚看到这个奇怪的简讯
I just... I got this weird
你在飞机上还是在哪里
message that you were on a plane or something?
是的 我提前回来了
Yeah. Yeah, I got out early.
真的
You did?
那你现在德国 还是哪里
So, what, are you in Germany, or... where?
不 我在这 我
No, I'm here. I'm...
我就本地
I'm stateside.
你回家了
You're home?
那 那你在干什么
What... what are you doing?
我只是觉得我需要一点儿时间
I guess I just needed a minute.
克里斯 孩子们都
Chris, the... the kids
非常想念你 已经九个月了
are dying to see you. It's been nine months.
我就回来
I'm coming home.
你没事儿吧
Are you all right?
没 我没事儿
Yeah, I'm good.
回家吧 宝贝儿
Babe, come home. Okay?
你知道 我 我们都很想你
You know, we... we miss you.
好的
Okay.
嘿 克里斯
Hey, Chris?
宝贝
Babe.
那我 我出门了
Hon, I'm... I'm going outside.
- 去捡 - 再高一点
- Get it. - Higher.
宝贝 我又能见到你的脸了 看上去不错
Look at you. I can see your face again, babe. Looks good.
- 那就好 - 看起来有点不一样了
- Oh, good. - Looks different.
比赛是这周六
So the game's this Saturday.
他是全队个子最高的孩子
You know, he's the tallest kid on the team.
大夫说他有可能长到195
Doctor said he could be 6'4".
很难想象吧
Isn't that insane?
等不及想让你看看他打球  不过
I can't wait for you to see him play. I go so crazy, though,
每次别的孩子冲他犯规的时候我都气坏了
when the other kids jump on him.
我需要你在一边平复我一下
Like, I need you there as, like, a leveler,
你知道我意思吧
you know what I mean?
嘿 说不定你还可以教教他
Hey, maybe you could even coach, you know?
肯纳开始换牙了
'Kenna's gonna lose that tooth,
我很担心她睡觉或者别的什么时候
and I'm so worried she's gonna swallow it,
一不小心就把牙齿吞了
like, in her sleep or something.
不过她说愿意让你帮她拔牙 但只要你
And she said she'd let you pull it, but only you.
你会帮她拔吗
Would you do that?
克里斯
Chris!
你妻子给我打了电话 说了些有趣的事情
I got a very interesting phone call. It's from your wife.
她和我讲了那次烧烤发生的事儿
She told me about the barbecue.
那真是不幸
Yeah, that was unfortunate. Yeah.
事情好像有点失控
Things seem like they got a little out of hand.
- 你担心吗 - 不 先生
- Are you worried? - No, sir.
所以你既不担心过去也不担心将来所发生的事吗
So you're not worried about what happened, or what might happen?
不 先生 我不担心那些
No, sir, I'm not worried about that.
让我问你一个问题 克里斯
Let me ask you a question, Chris.
你外驻了多长时间
How much time did you spend in-country?
- 去了四次 所以 - 那大约一千多天吗
- Well, four tours, so... - That's like, what, 1,000 days?
差不多是这样
Yeah, sounds about right.
如果我告诉你根据海军的记录
Would you be surprised if I told you
你一共击毙了160多个敌人 你会感到吃惊吗
that the Navy has credited you with over 160 kills?
你是否曾经想过
Do you ever think that...
你在那所见的和所做的一些事情
you might have seen things or
是你希望你不曾做过的
done some things over there that you wish you hadn't?
不 这不是我的风格
Oh, that's not me. No.
- 为什么不是 - 我只是在保护我的同袍
- What's not you? - I was just protecting my guys.
而敌人想杀我们的士兵 而且
They were trying to kill our soldiers, and...
我对杀的每一个人
I'm willing to meet my
都问心无愧
creator and answer for every shot that I took.
而真正萦绕在我心头的
The thing that...
是那些我没有能救下来的人
haunts me are all the guys that I couldn't save.
我愿意也能够再回去
You know, I'm willing and able to be there,
但我没有 我回家了 我退出了
but I'm not. I'm here. I quit.
所以你希望你能救更多的人
So you wish you could've saved more guys?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
你可以在这医院随便走走
You know, you can walk down any hall in this hospital.
你会看到大批的士兵等待救护
We got plenty of soldiers need saving.
你想去看看吗
Wanna take a walk?
好的
Sure.
那好 我正好给你看点儿东西
All right. I wanna show you something.
我还在抽烟
I still smoke.
请不要生气 一定程度上来说抽烟保住了我的右手
Can't be too mad at it 'cause it kinda saved my right hand.
怎么说
How so?
当爆炸发生的时候
When I got blown up, I had both
我本来双手都放在方向盘上
of my hands on the bottom of the steering wheel.
但就在爆炸前 我右手离开了方向盘
And right before the explosion went off, I took my hand off,
摸了一只烟 塞到嘴里
grabbed a cigarette, stuck it in my mouth.
当我正在点烟的时候 车炸了
And when I went to go light it, the explosion happened.
整个方向盘连同
And it took the whole bottom
我的左手都被炸飞了
of the steering wheel and my left hand off.
所以我很幸运右手还在
And I was lucky that I had this.
虽然右手也受了伤 但
I mean, it still fucked up my right hand, but...
- 看出来了 - 我还有右手
- Yeah. - ...I still got it.
- 所以你继续抽烟 - 是啊 我继续抽
- And you still smoke? - Yeah, I still smoke.
没击中 向右移动三英寸
Miss. Three inches to the right.
加油 韦恩 你可以做的更好
Come on, Wynn. You can do better than that.
把这个朝右调一点儿
Bring this to the right.
两只眼都睁着 结果会让你吃惊的
Make sure you keep both eyes open. Let that trigger surprise you.
我们又不是在杀敌人 只是在打靶
We're not shooting bad guys. We're shooting paper.
传奇你别对我指手画脚的好吗
How about The Legend stops trying to fuck up my shot?
- 那样如何 - 不如你先开一枪试试
- How about that? - How about you hit one?
- 命中 - 这就对了
- Hit! - There you go.
正中靶心 好家伙
Bull's eye, boy. Damn,
我觉得我信心大增啊
if that don't feel like I got my balls back.
你为什么老和我们混在一起呢
Why you spending all this time with us, man?
我知道你有家小的
I know you got a family.
我听说你参军前热衷收集靴子
I heard you had a boot collection before the war?
所以我在想 以前我们尺码一样
So I was thinking, I saw we were about the same size.
说真的 为何你要这样做
Seriously, man. Why do you do it?
我们互相照顾 对嘛
Well, we take care of each other, right?
看看如果你连射怎么样
Let's see if you can't hit two in a row.
来吧 你可以的
Come on, man. You got this.
- 命中 - 漂亮
- Hit! - Nice.
- 命中 - 他妈的
- Hit! - Goddamn.
现在到底谁才是传奇呢
Who's the legend now?
相信我 你不会想要这个头衔的
That's a title you don't want. Trust me.
你要跳下来吗 你拿这个
Yo, will you hop down? I'll give 'em to you.
- 你再加一个吗 - 可以
- You add one more? - Yeah.
- 好了 把他们搬进去吧 - 好的
- All right, take 'em inside. - All right.
来这儿
Come here.
在这生活还不错吧
It's not a bad life out here, is it?
他笑了
Got a smile on his face.
他看上去很开心
Looks cheery to me.
做着自己的事情
Just doing his thing.
跟他挥手说再见吧
Wave goodbye to him.
靠 谁呀
Oh! Fuck, who is that?!
- 宝贝儿 是你吗 - 是我 就是我
- Oh! Babe, is that you? - Yep-A-Doo-Dee!
- 宝贝儿 我受伤了 妈的 - 什么
- Baby, I fucking hurt myself. Shit. - What?
没事儿 我没事儿 妈的
No, I'm all right. I'm all right! I'm all right. Fuck.
- 宝贝儿 我很抱歉 - 没事儿
- Baby, I'm sorry. - It's okay.
怎么了 是不是
What happened? Don't...
你知道夺走一条生命是件很糟糕的事
You know that it's a heck of a thing to stop a beating heart.
我知道
Yeah.
所以你第一次我们一起来
That's why we're gonna do it together for your first time.
好的
All right.
记住 你要冷静
Now, remember, you gotta be calm...
自信
confident...
永远不要犹豫
and you never hesitate.
- 好的 - 你明白了吗 老弟
- All right. - You got it, bubba?
- 我明白了 - 你感觉还好吗
- I got it. - You feel good?
很好
Yeah.
2013年2月2日
把手举起来 小妞儿
Hands in the air, little lady.
把手举起来
Hands in the air.
然后把你衬裤脱下来
Now, you drop them drawers.
优美又缓慢地脱下来
But you drop 'em nice and easy.
宝贝儿 看看你
Oh, baby, look at you.
- 看看你 - 瞧你这样儿
- Look at you. - Look at you.
我能告诉你一点儿事儿吗
Can I tell you something?
- 你到时候和法官去说 - 别玩了
- Tell it to the judge. - Stop it.
我为你骄傲 我不知道该怎么说
No. I am so proud of you, and I don't tell you enough.
我真的为你骄傲 你是个好爸爸
I'm so proud of you. And you're such a great father.
而我很高兴我丈夫终于回来了
And I am so happy that I've got my husband back.
因为我知道你是多么的努力才做到这一切
And I also know how hard you fought to get here.
你值得我这样
You're worth fighting for.
你能回答我一个问题吗
Now tell me one other thing.
你是不是刻意把这条牛仔裤折上的
Did you... did you pleat those jeans?
是的 夫人 我相信正好折在正中了
Yes, ma'am. I believe they're right down the middle.
哦 你又是一个合格的老派牛仔了
Oh, you're just a regular old cowboy again.
你说对了 要不你
That's right. Now, why don't you...
要不你真的把衬裤脱了
why don't you really drop them drawers?
我根本就没有穿衬裤 宝贝儿
I'm not wearing any drawers, baby.
我有四分钟
I got four minutes.
那只需要花四分钟吗
Is that all it takes?
不 只需要两分钟
No, it takes two minutes.
剩下的两分钟我想好好地看看你
But then again I want two minutes to look at you.
你不是要去靶场吗
Aren't you going to the range?
你要带谁去
Who are you taking out?
这个士兵 他的妈妈一直在求我
This marine. His mama kept asking me.
她把车停在小学
She parks cars at the elementary school,
然后她说 你能帮助我的儿子吗
and she said, "Can you help out my son?"
然后我就想
And I just thought...
只有当下是我能真正掌控的 所以
today's the only day I can really do it, so...
这只会占用下午一小点时间 我就会回来
It's gonna be just a little bit of the afternoon. I'll be back.
是的
Yes!
- 你要保证你穿了衬裤 - 爸爸
- You make sure you keep them drawers... - Daddy.
- 怎么了 - 爸爸 一起玩宝贝龙冒险好不好
- What's up? What's up? - Dad, you wanna play Skylanders?
我现在不能玩 我回来的时候再玩
No, I can't play right now. I'll do it when I get back, boy.
但是 看 你已经第八关了 那可不行
But, see, you're on level 8, and that doesn't work.
我才过了第四关 我不想
I gotta be on level 4. And I don't want...
我想赢 你得让我赢
I wanna win. You gotta let me win.
没门
No way!
- 刺那只熊 - 刺什么
- Poke the bear! - Poke the what?
- Poke the bear! - Poke the what?!
刺那只熊
Poke the bear!
不 你应该咆哮 像这样
No! You're supposed to roar, like...
像什么 像个野兽对吗 像什么
Like what? Like a beast, right? Like what?
好吧 老弟 照顾好她们
All right, bubba. Y'all look after our women, okay?
- 好的 - 这可是重大的责任
- Yeah. - Okay. It's a big responsibility.
你准备好了吗
You up for it?
好吧 一会见 宝贝
All right. See you later, baby.
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you back.
- 你好吗 还好吧 - 很好
- How are you? You good? - Good.
我们准备开两小时的车然后开几枪
We're gonna go about a two-hour drive and shoot some guns
也许路上还能聊聊天 你觉得如何
and maybe have a little conversation along the way. What you say?
- 不错 - 好吧 我们走
- Yeah. - All right. Let's go.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
- Thank you. - Yep.
嘿 你吃过了吗 饿不 想要点什么路上吃吗
Hey, you eat yet? You hungry? You wanna get something on the way?
也就是那天克里斯·凯尔被他试图想帮助的人所杀